Good morning. So today we do the Sino -Russian Revolution.
早上好。今天我们来讲中俄革命。
And as I mentioned in previous classes,
正如我在前两课提到的，
it was really Dante who
正是达·安特才是关键。
helped give birth to the idea of modernity.
帮助诞生了现代性的概念。
And he really launched three major movements, which include the Renaissance,
他确实发起了三大运动，分别是文艺复兴、宗教改革以及中俄革命。
the Protestant Reformation, and the Sino -Russian Revolution.
We would not have modernity without Dante.
若无达·安特，现代性也就不存在。
Alright, so let's see how the three connect together.
好了，接下来看看三者如何相互联系。
We're going to review the previous two classes
我们将回顾前两课内容。
to connect to today's class on the Sino -Russian Revolution.
连接到今天关于中俄革命的课程。
So the Renaissance, what it was,
于是文艺复兴，它是什么，
was a celebration of what makes us human.
就是庆祝人类之本。
Before we were focused on the divine,
在此之前我们聚焦于神性，
on the idea of God.
聚焦于神的概念。
Now we want to tell the story of what it means to be human.
现在我们要讲述成为人类的意义。
That's the Renaissance. Protestantism believes
那就是文艺复兴。新教派认为我们能直接接触上帝。
that we have direct access to God.
天主教派认为我们能直接接触上帝。教皇即是神的代表。
The Catholic religion believes that we have direct access to God. The Pope is the divine representative.
And the clergy is the
教士是神的发言人。
spokesperson for God.
但新教派认为我们能直接接触上帝。
But Protestantism believes that we have direct access to God.
We should be able to speak with God directly through the Bible.
我们应该能通过圣经直接与上帝对话。
The Sino -Russian Revolution,
中俄革命
it's really about how can we know God.
这实际上是关于我们如何认识上帝。
Okay? That's the idea of the Sino -Russian Revolution.
好的？这就是中俄革命的核心思路。
So let's review why we have these ideas.
接下来我们回顾一下这些想法的由来。
And it has to do with Dante.
这与但丁的作品有关。
So remember last week we discussed the dialogue between Beatrice
记住上周我们讨论了贝娅特丽丝的对话
and Dante.
和但丁。
Let's review it really quickly.
我们快速回顾一下。
So Beatrice is saying,
于是贝娅特丽丝说，
I just said that God is perfect.
我刚才说上帝是完美的。
Whatever God touches, whatever God creates is perfect.
无论上帝触及何物，何物由上帝所造，皆为完美。
So if that's the case, why is it that there is decay?
若是如此，何以致有衰败？
Destruction and death in this world.
此世界的毁灭与死亡。
What are the forces that
是什么力量
give rise to this decay?
产生这衰败的是什么？
And then she explains,
然后她解释，
okay, whatever God creates is perfect.
好的，凡是上帝所造的都是完美的。
So angels are perfect. They're immortal.
所以天使是完美的。他们是永生的。
They're eternal. But the elements
它们是永恒的。但这世界里的元素
that are in this world,
在此世界中的元素
they are not created by God.
它们不是上帝所造的。
What is created by God are the divine laws.
上帝所造的是神圣之法。
The laws that underlie the universe.
这些法则是宇宙之根。
God created the atoms. God created the laws
上帝造了原子。上帝造了让原子相互作用的法则。
that allow these atoms to interact with each other.
好的？于是光线与…】
Okay? So the rays and
motion of the holy light draw forth the soul of every animal
圣光的运动把每个动物的灵魂拉出，并把植物从能成形的物质中取出。
and plant from matter able to take form.
于是就是这些神圣之法造出了动物和植物。
So it's these divine laws that create the animals and the plants.
But these divine laws also necessitate
但这些神圣之法也必然导致
that they die in order for new forms to come into being.
它们死亡，以便让新的形态出现。
Okay? So this is the idea of evolution.
好吧？这就是进化的概念。
We humans are special,
我们人类是特殊的，
why? Because
为什么？因为
we are both divinely created,
我们既是神所造的
and created by the laws of the universe.
并由宇宙定律所造。
We have a dual nature, and
我们拥有双重本性，且
the main advantage of this dual nature is, it gives us a capacity to imagine.
这种双重本性的主要优势是，它赋予我们想象的能力。
Remember, the issue of God is that God is perfect.
记住，关于上帝的问题是上帝是完美的。
If you're perfect,
若你是完美的，
if you're eternal, if you're immutable, you lack an imagination
若你是永恒的，若你是不变的，你就缺乏想象。
because there are no boundaries to you.
因为你没有边界。
But if you're human, you're forced to have an imagination
但若你是人类，你就必须有想象力。
because you'll make mistakes.
因为你会犯错。
You will fail. There are things that you do not know.
你会失败。有些事你不知道。
And the imagination gives you the capacity to know this world
想象力让你能认识这个世界
and to perfect this world.
并把它完善。
So that's what it means to be fundamentally human.
于是这才是根本人类的意义。
So let's recap.
好了，回顾一下。
These are the three main messages that Dante is relaying to us through his poetry.
这些是但丁通过诗歌传递给我们的三条主旨。
First of all, God is within us.
首先，神在我们之内。
How do we know? Because we are capable of loving others.
我们怎么知道？因为我们能爱他人。
God is the light of love within us.
神是我们内在的爱之光。
The more we love someone, the more this light grows in us.
我们越爱一个人，内在的光就越发亮。
So we must focus on loving someone who is dear to us.
于是我们要把精力放在爱我们亲近的人上。
Second idea is we have the imagination and
第二个想法是我们拥有想象力。
thus responsibility to discover the universal laws underlying reality.
于是我们承担起发现支撑现实的普遍规律的责任。
God created the laws of the universe.
神创造了宇宙的规律。
God created us in order to know these laws.
神造我们是为了认识这些规律。
That's very fundamental to the idea of science.
这非常是科学观念的根本。
The last idea is we can master these laws to better our reality.
最后一个观念是我们能掌握这些规律，以更好地改造我们的现实。
So these are the three hidden messages of divine comedy
于是这便是神剧的三条隐秘信息。
that will influence the development of science in the Western world.
这将影响西方科学的发展。
So I want to talk briefly about science.
于是我想简要谈谈科学。
It has been traditionally practiced.
它一直被传统实践着。
It is a very important practice in ancient societies.
它在古代社会中是一项非常重要的实践。
So in ancient societies,
于是，在古代社会中，主要的古文明有中国，…】
the major ancient civilizations are China,
}
Egypt, and India. And
埃及与印度。还有
you will see a lot of similarities among
你会看到三大文明在实践科学观念时的诸多相似之处。
these three civilizations on how they practice the idea of science.
这些文明在科学实践上的相似之处。
It's very intuitive. It's very imaginative.
很直观，很有想象力。
It will make sense to you.
会让你明白。
So the first science that
于是第一门科学是
they focus a lot on is the idea of sacred geometry.
他们非常关注的是神圣几何学的概念。
I'm not sure if you've heard of this.
我不确定你是否听说过。
But the idea of sacred geometry is that
但神圣几何学的概念是……
the underlying fundamental structure of the universe,
宇宙的基本结构，
of reality, are geometric shapes.
现实的基本结构，都是几何形状。
And from these geometric shapes,
从这些几何形状开始，
you can give rise to every possible reality.
你可以让它产生所有可能的现实。
So this is called the egg of life.
于是它被称为生命之卵。
And from the egg of life, you just keep on expanding it.
从生命之卵开始，你只需不断扩展它。
You will get all three.
你会得到全部三种。
These are all three of reality. These are actually 3D,
这些都是三维的现实，实际上是三维的，四维的形状。我无法示例，但...
4D shapes. I can't illustrate them, but
4D shapes. I can'tillustrate them, but
if you're curious, go online.
如果你好奇，可以上网搜索。
These are beautiful ideas.
这些都是美妙的想法。
So there are two possible ways to understand sacred geometry.
于是有两种可能的方式来理解神圣几何。
The first possible way is to understand as solids.
第一种可能的方式是把它们理解为固体。
So the Egyptians understood them as solids, and
于是埃及人把它们理解为固体，随后也如此。
Plato understood them as solids.
柏拉图也把它们理解为固体。
Remember Plato? A lot of people don't know that.
记得柏拉图吗？很多人不知道。
But Plato's philosophy is derived from the Egyptians.
但柏拉图的哲学源自埃及人。
And the idea of sacred geometry, it's very apparent in Plato's writings.
而神圣几何的概念，在柏拉图的著作中非常明显。
And he got this from the Egyptians.
他从埃及人那里得到的。
So basically the idea is that
基本上就是这个想法：
if you train yourself on how to understand sacred geometry
如果你训练自己去理解神圣几何。
and how to manipulate sacred geometry in your head, you can access God.
并且学会在脑中操纵神圣几何，你就能接触上帝。
So the first idea is to understand it as solids.
于是第一步是把它当作固体来理解。
But there's another way you can understand sacred geometry.
另外还有另一种方式来理解神圣几何。
And it's as vibrations. Vibrations.
并且是振动。振动。
As energy. As a force.
如能量。如一股力。
And this is the way that the Chinese understand sacred geometry.
而这就是中国人理解神圣几何的方式。
As chi. As life force.
如气。作为生命力。
As well as the Hindus.
以及印度人。
And so imagine a monk who's breathing.
于是想象一个正在呼吸的僧人。
Who's meditating. What is he doing?
谁在冥想？他在做什么？
He's breathing and he's meditating
他在呼吸，正在冥想
and he's focusing his energies in order to achieve the sacred geometry within him.
他把能量聚焦，以求在内成就神圣几何
The monk will often say things like, oh, oh.
僧人常会说：哦，哦。
Oh, oh,
哦，哦，
oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
哦，哦，哦，哦，哦。
oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦
oh, oh, oh, oh, Why is he doing this?
哦，哦，哦，哦，为什么他这么做？
Because the belief at this time is that
因为此时的信念是……
if there is a God,
如果有神，
if there's a creator God,
如果有造物神，
the question is how does it think?
问题是它怎么思考？
It's not going to think with words the way we do.
它不会像我们那样用文字来思考。
It's going to think using mathematics, with sacred geometry.
它将用数学思考，配以神圣几何。
And by thinking,
并且通过思考，
he is going to create the underlying universe.
他将创造基础宇宙。
And how does he do that?
他是怎么做到的？
He does it by breathing. Breathing in,
他通过呼吸完成。吸气，发出神圣几何，再呼气，重新吸气。
emitting sacred geometry, and then breathing out, breathing back in.
emitting sacred geometry, and thenbreathing out, breathing back in.
Inhaling, exhaling. And this will give rise to the universe.
吸气，呼气。这样就会产生宇宙。
So if you're a monk or a priest,
所以如果你是僧人或祭司，
you practice meditation in order to
你练习冥想是为了
try to mimic the activity of the mind.
尝试模仿心灵的活动。
And if you are able to succeed, then
如果你能成功，那就……
what will happen is you harmonize yourself with the vibrations of the universe.
所发生的事是你与宇宙的振动和谐。
And therefore, you're able to access divine energy.
于是你就能获得神圣能量。
So that's the idea of sacred geometry.
这就是神圣几何的概念。
And again, it's a very complicated idea,
再说一次，这个想法很复杂，
but that's a general gist.
但大体意思就是这样。
Any questions?
还有什么问题吗？
And again, this should make intuitive sense.
再说一次，这个想法应该很直观。
This should make intuitive sense to you.
这应该对你很直观。
The second big field that the Egyptians,
第二个大领域是埃及人，
the Chinese, and
中国人，和
the Indians were really
印度人真的
passionate about is astronomy and astrology.
热衷于天文学与占星术。
So the Egyptians basically created astrology.
于是埃及人基本上创造了占星术。
And the idea is that you're trying to link the movement of the stars, the cosmos,
其核心思想是把星体运动、宇宙与世间事件相连。
with events in the world.
So by understanding the movement of the stars,
于是通过了解星体运动，
you're able to divine or predict the future of humanity.
你就能预知人类的未来。
Every major king had an astrologist
每位大王都请了占星师。
in order to divine the future through the practice of astronomy and astrology.
为通过天文与占星术的实践预知未来。
And the last thing is alchemy.
最后一项是炼金术。
What is alchemy? Alchemy is basically chemistry
炼金术是什么？炼金术基本上就是化学。
and sorcery combined together.
与魔法合并在一起。
This is a polytheistic world.
这是一个多神论的世界。
And the idea is that because
其想法是因为
it's a polytheistic world, it's a chaotic world.
这是一个多神论的世界，也是一个混沌的世界。
And somehow, if you're clever enough, you're able to do it.
只要足够机巧，你就能做到。
You're able to hack this world.
你就能破解这个世界。
Think of it as hacking.
把它想象成破解。
That there are secrets to this world.
这世界里有秘密。
And you are able to take elements in this world,
你可以把世界里的元素拿出来。
combine together, and create something called the philosopher's stone.
合在一起，制造出一种叫做哲人之石的东西。
The philosopher's stone is the power of God in
哲人之石是上帝的力量在……
order to give you the elixir of immortality,
以此给你不死的灵丹。
in order to live forever, as well as to manipulate the environment.
为永生而做，也为操纵环境而做。
So basically, it turned lead into gold.
基本上，它把铅变成了金。
And again, this was an extremely popular practice.
再一次，这是一种极为流行的做法。
And it was a very popular practice. And it was a very popular practice in ancient societies.
它是一种非常流行的做法，古代社会里也很受欢迎。
So these are three major sciences in the primitive societies.
于是这三门学科就是原始社会的三大科学。
China, Egypt, and India.
中国、埃及与印度。
And they promulgated outwards
并向外宣扬
and influenced other societies.
并影响其他社会
We still have them today.
我们今天仍然拥有它们
There are still people who practice alchemy,
还有人练习炼金术
sacred geometry,
神圣几何学
and astrology today.
占星术
Any questions about this before I move on?
还有什么问题吗？
Okay, so this is primitive science.
好的，这就是原始科学。
So the question then is, what's the difference?
那么问题是，区别在哪里？
Okay, so let's focus on the three major differences between pre -modern science
好的，让我们聚焦在前现代科学与现代科学的三大差异上。
and modern science. The first major difference is,
第一个主要差异是，
it focuses on the spiritual world, on the outer worldly.
它聚焦于精神世界，外在世界。
And the point of science was to create harmony between our world
并且科学的要点是让我们的世界与精神世界和谐相处。
and the spiritual world.
因为若能让这两世界相和，便能拥有更繁荣的世界。
Because if you harmonize these two worlds, you can have a more prosperous world.
A more prosperous, more peaceful future.
更繁荣、更和平的未来。
Today, we are only focused on the material world.
今天，我们只关注物质世界。
The world that we can see and know.
我们能看到并了解的世界。
In order to create progress.
为了创造进步。
We've abandoned the spiritual world and
我们已放弃精神世界，且
we focus on this material world in order to manipulate it.
我们聚焦于此物质世界以操纵它。
In order to promote technological progress.
为促进技术进步。
And quite honestly, we have been extremely successful at that.
说实话，我们在这方面非常成功。
In fact, I will argue we've been too successful at that.
实际上，我认为我们在这方面已经太成功了。
Okay? So that's the first major difference between pre -modern and modern science.
好的？这就是前现代与现代科学的第一个主要区别。
Second major difference is that
第二个主要区别是……
pre -modern science relies entirely on intuition
前现代科学完全依赖直觉。
and imagination. Okay? You don't do experiments.
并且想象。好吧？你不做实验。
You don't have conferences.
你没有会议。
You don't debate. You just meditate.
你不辩论。你只是冥想。
You just dream. Okay?
你只是在做梦。好吧？
And you often fall into trances in order to communicate with the spiritual world.
然后你经常进入恍惚状态，以便与灵界沟通。
In this world, they use a lot of...
在那个世界里，他们大量使用……
Hello... Hello...
你好……你好……
Pseudonics. Okay? They...
伪音学。好吧？它们……
A lot of psychedelics.
大量的迷幻药物。
Okay? Including magic mushrooms.
好的？包括魔法蘑菇。
A drink called soma.
一种叫做soma的饮料。
Which is very important in the Hindu religion.
在印度教中非常重要。
As well as the Zoroastrian religion.
以及祆罗教。
It's basically a psychedelic.
它基本是迷幻药。
Okay? Today,
好的？今天，
we don't rely on intuition and imagination.
我们不依赖直觉和想象。
We think this is superstitious.
我们认为这很迷信。
We rely mainly on something called the seven principles.
我们主要依赖一种叫做七原则的东西。
Okay? And...
好的？还有……
And... And... Later on,
还有……还有……之后，
I will discuss the seven method more in detail.
我会更详细地讨论七种方法。
All right? Now, last thing is...
好的？现在，最后一件事是……
In pre -modern science,
在前现代科学中，
people are relying on divine inspiration in order to discover the truth.
人们依靠神灵启示来发现真理。
The big question is, what is truth?
大问题是，什么是真理？
Today, we care about the question,
今天我们关注的问题是，
how do we know truth?
我们如何知道真理？
Okay? It's really the idea of...
好的？这真的是个想法……
The institutionalization of doubt.
怀疑的制度化
Our main priority is to question and
我们的首要任务是提问
doubt the truth.
怀疑真理。
And what will happen is,
接下来会发生的事是，
because of this emphasis change,
因为这个重心转移，
we've changed from what is truth to how do we know truth,
我们已从“真理是什么”转到“我们如何知道真理”，
it will launch a revolution in technological progress.
它将掀起技术进步的革命。
All right? All right.
好的？好的。
So, underlying the seven revolution are three major things.
于是，七大革命的基础是三件主要事物。
First, the idea of monotheism.
首先，单神论的概念。
The idea of monotheism is that there is one God.
单神论的概念是：只有一位神。
Okay? And, again,
好的？再说一次，
the very idea of monotheism is also revolutionary in human thought.
单神论的概念本身在人的思想里也是一次革命。
Second idea is that God designed
第二个概念是上帝的设计。
and willed the universe into being.
并将宇宙赋予存在。
So, there is one God. So, there is an intelligent design to the universe.
于是有一位神，宇宙也有智能设计。
And it's up to us to discover this design.
而我们则去发现这设计。
God endowed us with the capacity to discover his design and will.
上帝赋予我们发现其设计与意志的能力。
Okay? So, these are the three major theological assumptions underlying the second revolution. That
好？所以，这三大神学假设构成了第二次革命的基础。那就是第二次革命在西欧发生的原因。
is why the second revolution happened in Western Europe
and not, say, in China or the Islamic world or India.
并且，例如在中国、伊斯兰世界或印度。
Okay? Because you needed these three theological assumptions.
好？因为你需要这三大神学假设。
Okay. So, what do these assumptions bring us?
好。于是，这些假设给我们带来了什么？
Okay. So, let's look at polytheism.
好的。那我们来看看多神论。
Again, throughout most of human history,
再说一次，在人类历史的大部分里，
most societies have been polytheistic.
大多数社会都是多神论的。
What is the difference between a polytheistic worldview of science
科学的多神论世界观与单神论世界观有什么区别？
and a monotheistic worldview of science?
以及单神论的科学世界观？
Okay? So, I need you to memorize this chart. Okay?
好？所以，我需要你记住这张图表。好？
The first major difference is a polytheistic system is a system of There's really no design.
第一个主要区别是多神论体系是一个没有设计的体系。
There's really no progress.
实际上没有进步。
It's just chaos and struggle.
它只是混沌与争斗。
But in a monotheistic worldview,
但在单神论的世界观中，
there is an underlying truth to the universe.
有一种潜在的宇宙真理。
Okay? That's the first difference.
好？这就是第一个区别。
The second major difference is the idea of randomness.
第二个主要区别是随机性的概念。
Things happen for no particular reason.
事情发生没有特定原因。
If you win the lottery, that's great.
如果你中彩票，那就太好了。
Okay? But if you lose all your wealth, that's just random.
好？但如果你把所有财产都输掉，那就只是随机。
Okay? It's just fate.
好的？这只是命运。
It's just destiny. There's no purpose or no design to your fate.
这只是宿命。没有目的，也没有设计。
But, in a monotheistic world, there's the idea of good and evil.
但在一神论的世界里，存在善与恶的概念。
Things happen to you that benefit you if you're doing good.
若你行善，事会对你有利。
But if you're doing evil, then bad things will happen to you.
若你行恶，事则会对你不利。
Okay? So, there's a very, there's a deep sense
好？所以，真的有一种很深的感觉
that God is in our lives orchestrating events.
神在我们的生活中安排着事件。
Okay? And the last major difference is that between fate and progress.
好？最后一个主要区别是命运与进步之间。
Okay? If there's truth in this world,
好？如果这个世界里有真理，
if there's goodness in this world, then
如果这个世界里有善，
we have a responsibility to progress by doing good
我们就有责任通过行善来推动进步。
and by discovering this truth.
并且通过发现这真理。
Okay? That's why I keep on emphasizing this,
好？这就是我一直强调的原因，
but monotheism is really an intellectual revolution, first and foremost.
但单神论确实是首要的知识革命。
Okay. So, the Second Revolution happens.
好的。于是第二次革命发生了。
And what drives it?
它的驱动力是什么？
Okay? There are three major forces that drive the Second Revolution.
好的？第二次革命有三大驱动力。
The first is the idea of the Protestant Reformation
第一条是新教改革的概念以及反改革的概念。
and the Counter -Reformation.
第二条是新教改革的概念以及反改革的概念。
So, the Protestants have come and they're challenging the authority of the Church.
第三条是新教改革的概念以及反改革的概念。
And the Church responds by what's called the Counter -Reformation.
于是教会以所谓的反宗教改革作回应。
There is this belief, or there's this prejudice,
有一种信念，或者说是一种偏见，认为教会是反科学的。
that the Church is anti -Science.
that the Churchis anti -Science.
The Catholic Church is not anti -Science.
天主教会并非反科学。
In fact, both the Protestants and
事实上，基督教改革者和天主教会都在利用科学来巩固自己的合法性与权威。
the Catholic Church are trying to use Science in order to promote their legitimacy and authority.
他们都把科学当作巩固自身权威的工具。
Okay? So, the Protestants are heavily devoted to Science
好的？所以，基督教改革者非常投入科学。
because they want to understand the will and mind of God.
因为他们想了解上帝的意志与心思。
The Catholics themselves are also promoting Science.
天主教会本身也在推广科学。
The Catholics will create a new society called the Jesuits,
天主教会将创建一个名为耶稣会的新社会，
who are renowned for being great scientists.
耶稣会以其杰出的科学家而闻名。
In fact, a lot of universities in this world were founded by Jesuits.
事实上，世界上许多大学都是耶稣会创办的。
A lot of Jesuits came to China and they promoted knowledge
大量耶稣会士来到中国，推动了知识与科学的发展。
and Science in China.
他们在中国推广知识与科学。
And this has been true for many centuries.
这一点已持续了数百年。
Okay? So, both the Catholic Church and the Protestant movement,
好的？所以，天主教会和新教运动都在争夺科学的使用权，以此来提升自己的权威与合法性。
they are in a struggle to use Science in order to promote their own authority
他们正利用科学来巩固自身的权威与合法性。
and legitimacy. Okay? So, that's the first major force driving the Revolution.
好的？这就是推动革命的首要力量。
Second is war.
第二个是战争。
During this time, Europe is in constant state of war.
在此期间，欧洲处于持续的战争状态。
It's fighting amongst themselves, between the Catholics and the Protestants.
他们彼此争斗，天主教会与新教派之间交战。
It's also fighting with the Muslims, okay?
它也在与穆斯林作战，好的？
The Ottoman Empire, which is, at this point,
奥斯曼帝国，此时已是世界上最强大的帝国。
the strongest empire in the world.
All right? And the last idea that's driving Science is the age of exploration
好的？最后推动科学的想法是探险与征服时代。
and conquest.
随着欧洲向外扩张，…
As Europe is trying to expand outwards,
As Europe is tryingto expand outwards,
if they're going to North America, they're going to South America,
如果他们要去北美，就得去南美，
they need better navigation tools.
他们需要更好的航海工具。
They need compasses.
他们需要罗盘。
They need astrolabes, okay?
他们需要星盘，好的？
So, Science solves all three problems.
于是，科学解决了这三大问题。
Okay? Okay, so,
好的？好的，接着说，
again, the Second Revolution,
再次，第二次革命，
the best way to know the Second Revolution is,
了解第二次革命的最佳方式是，
it's a fundamental change from asking,
它是从提问到回答的根本变化，
what is truth, to, how do we know truth?
什么是真理，怎样知道真理？
Okay? How can we know truth?
好的？怎样知道真理？
Okay? How can we know truth? And, believe it or not,
好的？怎样知道真理？而且，信不信得了，
but no one really bothered to ask this question before.
但没有人真正去问过这个问题。
How can we know truth? Okay?
我们怎样知道真理？好的吗？
And because Science is asking this question,
因为科学正在问这个问题，
how do we know truth, what it's really doing is,
我们怎样知道真理，真正的做法是，
it's separating itself from religion and
它把自己与宗教分离，并且
putting itself above religion, okay?
把自己置于宗教之上，好的吗？
Because religion purports to be the truth, right?
因为宗教自称是真理，对吧？
And what Science is saying is, like, how do you know if you're right?
而科学所说的，是，像是，怎样知道你是否正确？
Well, we know if you're right.
好吧，我们知道你是否正确。
Because we have methods to test you, okay?
因为我们有方法来检验你，好吗？
So, Science is putting itself above religion.
于是，科学把自己置于宗教之上。
And, as you can imagine,
而且，正如你所想象的那样。
this will create conflicts within the Catholic Church very,
这将很快在天主教会内部造成冲突，
very soon, mainly in the trial of Galileo.
主要在伽利略的审判中。
Okay. So, because
好的。所以，因为
Science asked this question, how do we know truth,
科学提出了这个问题，如何知道真相？
what it does is it creates the Semitic Method, okay?
它的做法是创造了塞米提方法，好吗？
And the Semitic Method is composed of three main things.
塞米提方法由三件主要事物组成。
The first is you ask questions and you propose hypotheses.
第一步是你提问问题并提出假设。
So, there are no questions now that are out of bounds.
第二步是没有超出范围的问题。
And you have to think of solutions and ideas to solve these questions, okay?
然后你要想办法和点子来解决这些问题，好吗？
So, that's the first step. Second step is there are these processes
于是，第一步完成。第二步是有这些过程和流程来检验假设，
and protocols for testing hypotheses,
实验，基本上，全部对吗？
experimentation, basically, all right?
So, only if you can experiment,
于是，只有你能实验时，
only if you can, only if your hypothesis matches experiment,
只有你能实验，只有你的假设与实验相符时，
experiment results, can it be true.
实验结果，才算是真实。
Now, last thing is it creates a system of doubt
现在，最后一点是它创造了一套怀疑与批评的体系，以便检验所有实验结果。
and criticism in order to test all experimental results.
今天我们把它们称作学术团体和同行评议期刊，好吗？
And today, we call them academic societies and peer review journals, okay?
So, if you're a scientist working today at a university,
于是，如果你是今天在大学工作的科学家，
whatever results you have,
无论你得到什么结果，
you must first publish and then
你首先要发表，然后
you have to present your journal results to a conference of peers
你需要把期刊结果呈现给同行会议，他们会批评你。
who will criticize you. And they will look for flaws.
他们会寻找缺陷。
They will look for flaws. They will look for flaws in your argument. And
他们会寻找缺陷，检视你论证中的漏洞。
this is an extremely effective system on
这是一套极其有效的系统，能让我们知道什么是真实的。
how to know what is true.
再一次，因为这个系统，…。
And again, because of the system,
it's allowed for a remarkable explosion of wealth
它为今天世界的财富、技术和进步带来了显著的爆炸。
and technology and progress in the world today.
并且这张图表向我们展示了这一点。
And this is the chart that shows us, okay?
（两句合并）
So, for most of human history, progress,
于是，在人类历史的大部分里，进步，即生产力，基本保持平稳。
meaning productivity, has been flat.
然后从1700年左右开始，…。
And then starting around the year 1700,
it starts to exponentially rise,
它开始呈指数增长，
okay? And
好吧？而且
this has meant that we are now able to feed more and more people.
这意味着我们现在能够喂饱越来越多的人。
So, before 1700,
于是，在1700年前，
you really couldn't get above a few hundred million people.
你们真的只能达到几亿人。
And now, we are at nine, we are projected to reach nine billion people.
现在我们已达九亿，预计将达到九十亿人。
And you can ask, this is a good thing.
而你可以说，这是件好事。
And I will argue it's not a good thing.
我则认为这并非好事。
But it shows us the remarkable power of science, okay?
但它确实展示了科学的非凡力量。
Alright, so now the question then is,
好的，现在问题是，
what caused the subject method to arise?
是什么导致了主体方法的出现？
And it really has to do with a major debate among scientists.
这确实与科学家们之间的一场重大辩论有关。
It was the geocentric versus the heliocentric debate, okay?
它是地心说与日心说的辩论，好的？
Now, what's interesting is that,
现在，有趣的是，
if you look at the Egyptians,
如果你看看埃及人，
they knew that
他们知道太阳是宇宙的中心。
the sun was the center of the universe.
这就是他们的神是太阳神拉的原因，好的？
That's why their god was the sun god, Ra, okay?
But by the time you hit the Greeks,
但等你到达希腊人时，已经出现了两派的分歧，一派认为宇宙围着太阳转动。
there was now this divergence between those who believed
that the universe revolved around the sun
但等你到达希腊人时，已经出现了两派的分歧，一派认为宇宙围着太阳转动。
and those who believed it revolved around the earth.
以及那些认为它围绕地球转动的人。
In about 150,
大约在150年，
a Greek scientist, his name Ptolemy,
一位希腊科学家，名叫托勒密。
working in Egypt,
在埃及工作，
he developed the first comprehensive cosmological system.
他建立了第一个完整的宇宙论体系。
And this cosmological system,
而这个宇宙论体系，
which he wrote in a book called The Almagest,
他在一本叫《阿尔马格斯特》的书中写下了这些内容。
he made certain arguments.
他提出了一些论点。
Okay, the first argument is that
好的，第一个论点是……
the earth stands still, okay?
地球静止，好吗？
The earth does not move, it doesn't revolve, okay?
地球不动，也不自转，好吗？
Second is that all other celestial bodies,
第二点是其他天体，
including the moon, including the stars, the planets,
包括月球、星星、行星，它们以圆形运动绕地球转动。
revolve around the earth in a circular motion.
好的，为什么？因为在天上，…
Okay, why? Because in the heavens,
it is assumed that everything is perfect.
假设一切都完好无缺。
Okay, so for example, on planet earth,
好，举例来说，在地球上，
we breathe something called air, right?
我们呼吸的空气叫做空气，对吧？
Air, oxygen, is what gives us life.
空气，氧气，是赋予我们生命的东西。
But up there in space,
但在太空之上，
air becomes ether.
空气变成以太。
Ether is the air that the gods breathe.
以太是众神呼吸的空气。
Ether is what allows the world, the heavens, to be perfect.
以太使世界、天空完好无缺。
Okay? And so,
好？所以呢。
and this is the Arabic edition of The Almagest.
并且这是《阿尔马格斯特》的阿拉伯版。
And as you can see, there, you can't read this, but
正如你所见，那里你看不到这段，但……
there's a lot of mathematical detail in the book.
书中包含大量数学细节。
And because Ptolemy's perspective aligned with theology,
因为托勒密的视角与神学相符，与圣经相合，于是被接受，并被视为真理超过千年。
the Bible, it was accepted,
it was accepted true for over a thousand years, okay?
因为托勒密的视角与神学相符，与圣经相合，于是被接受，并被视为真理超过千年。
The Islamic golden age relied heavily on Ptolemy's understanding of the cosmos.
伊斯兰黄金时代在很大程度上依赖托勒密对宇宙的理解。
But the first person to suggest that
但第一个提出这一模型错误的人是哥白尼。
this model is wrong is Copernicus,
okay, who is a Polish polymath.
好的，谁是波兰的博学者。
He did many things. He did astrology.
他做了很多事。他做了占星术。
He also did astronomy, okay?
他也做了天文学，好的？
And when he died in 1543,
当他于1543年去世时，他提出了日心模型。
he proposed the heliocentric model.
现在，最重要的是我们记住的事是…
Now, what's really important for us to remember is
that Copernicus was a devout Catholic.
那时哥白尼是个虔诚的天主教徒。
And many of his friends were major figures within the Catholic Church.
他的许多朋友在天主教会内都是重要人物。
And guess what? They were extremely supportive of his theory.
你猜怎么着？他们对他的理论极为支持。
In fact, they wanted him to publish his theory.
事实上，他们想让他发表自己的理论。
Okay? Why?
好的？为什么？
Because at this point, there is no conflict between science
因为此时，科学与之无冲突。
and religion. So
与宗教。于是
the saying back then is,
当时的说法是，
it is the job of the church,
这就是教会的职责，
the Catholic Church, to tell you how to go to heaven,
天主教会，告诉你怎样去天堂，
not how the heavens go.
而不是天体如何运行。
Okay? So the Catholic Church didn't really care one way.
好吧？于是天主教会根本不在乎。
They didn't care about the heliocentric model.
他们不关心日心模型。
They didn't care at all. So, okay.
他们完全不关心。好了。
So Copernicus was heavily supportive.
于是哥白尼得到了大力支持。
The problem with Copernicus is that the mathematics didn't really make sense.
哥白尼的问题在于他的数学并不真正通顺。
Okay? So if I put two books in front of you,
好吧？如果我把两本书放在你面前，
Copernicus' book called On the Revolutions of the Celestial Spheres,
哥白尼的书叫《天体运行论》。
or Ptolemy's book, well, most scientists would tell you
或者托勒密的书，嗯，大多数科学家会告诉你
that Ptolemy's book is better.
托勒密的书更好。
Okay? There's more math. It's more well argued.
好吧？还有更多数学，论证更充分。
And the reason why is Copernicus, his idea is new.
于是，哥白尼的原因在于他的想法是新的。
And so there was not that much time.
于是就没有那么多时间。
He didn't have that much time to refine it.
他没有足够时间去完善它。
People didn't really have time to work on it.
人们没时间去研究它。
Whereas Ptolemy, thousands of people have been working on it over the centuries.
而托勒密，几千人百代在研究它。
Okay? So the heliocentric model, it is much more refined,
所以日心模型更精细。
much more accepted at this point than the heliocentric model.
此时比日心模型更被广泛接受。
This man, his name is Tycho Braque.
这位先生，名叫提霍·布拉赫。
And he is a Danish polymath as well.
他还是一位丹麦多才子。
He comes from a very noble family.
他来自一个非常高贵的家族。
And he spent a lot of his time doing observations.
他把大量时间用于观测。
Okay? He collected a lot of data.
好的？他收集了大量数据。
He observed how the planets revolved.
他观察到行星的运动。
And his conclusion is that
他的结论是：地心与日心模型都正确。
the geocentric and the heliocentric model are both correct.
And his proposal was that
他提出的方案是：
Earth was the center of the world,
地球是世界的中心，
but the planets revolved around the sun.
但行星绕太阳运动。
Okay? So the sun revolved around the Earth.
好的？于是太阳绕地球转动。
And every other system revolved around the Earth.
而其他一切天体也绕地球转动。
And every other system revolved around the sun. Okay?
而其他一切天体也绕太阳转动。好的？
So that's what he derived from his data.
于是他从数据中推导出这个结论。
Now, he had a prodigy named Johannes Kepler.
接着，他有个名叫约翰内斯·凯普勒的天才。
He's a German. And he looked at the data and
他是德国人，看到数据后……
he discovered that
他发现了
the data actually makes the heliocentric model,
数据实际上证明了日心模型，
actually supports the heliocentric model more than the geocentric model.
实际上比地心模型更支持日心模型。
But because he is not a member of the Catholic Church, he's a Lutheran, he doesn't have the power to do that.
但因为他不是天主教会的成员，他是路德宗的，才没有那种权力。
The Catholic Church couldn't really do anything about him.
天主教会对他也没什么能干的。
All right? And what's remarkable about Kepler is
好了？凯普勒的特别之处是……
that just from this data, he was able to make certain predictions about the stars
仅凭这些数据，他就能对星星做出某些预测
that we've confirmed over time.
我们随时间验证了这些预测
The first is that the sun,
第一点是太阳
so everything revolves around the sun.
于是万物都围着太阳转。
His problem, though, is that he didn't put the sun at the center of the universe.
他的难点在于，他没有把太阳放在宇宙的中心。
He put something else at the center of the universe.
他把别的东西放在宇宙的中心。
The sun revolved around that. And the Earth revolved around that.
太阳围着它转，地球也围着它转。
And the Earth is revolving around the sun. Second major law of planar motion is
地球围着太阳转。平面运动的第二大定律是
that the orbit is actually not circular.
轨道实际上并非圆形。
It's elliptical. OK?
它是椭圆的。好吗？
That's what the data was telling him.
数据正是这么告诉他的。
All right? And this goes against theology.
对吗？这与神学相冲突。
Because remember, in theology, the heavens are perfect.
因为记得，神学里天空是完美的。
Right? Because that's where God lives.
对吧？因为那里住着上帝。
But Kepler is saying, nope,
但开普勒说，没错，
the orbit is elliptical.
轨道是椭圆的。
And then what else he did that was revolutionary is
随后他做的另一件革命性事是
that he was able to make the universe, the universe, more elliptical.
他能把宇宙变得更椭圆。
And he discovered that there was a correlation between this orbit
他发现轨道与行星质量之间存在相关性。
and the mass of the planet.
好的？这将为牛顿的出现铺路。
OK? And this will give rise to Newton.
OK? And this willgive rise to Newton.
But Kepler made all these revolutionary discoveries.
但开普勒完成了所有这些革命性发现。
Now comes Galileo.
随后是伽利略。
And Galileo, he lives in Florence at this time.
伽利略此时住在佛罗伦萨。
And so he's under the purview of the Catholic Church.
于是他在天主教会的管辖之下。
So he comes from a pretty normal background.
他来自一个相当普通的背景。
When he grew up, he wanted to be a monk.
长大后，他想成为一名僧人。
But his dad wanted him to become a doctor instead.
但他的父亲想让他去读医学。
And then they made a compromise.
于是他们达成了折衷。
And he said, I'll go study mathematics.
他答道：我去学数学。
But his dad was insistent that he go study medicine.
但他的父亲坚持让他去读医学。
Eventually, Galileo managed to go do what he wanted
最终，伽利略终于实现了自己的愿望，专心做科学。
and just do science. OK?
好了，没问题。
At this point, they invented a telescope.
此时，他们发明了望远镜。
And this was not a great telescope.
这不是一台很好的望远镜。
So a telescope could give you three times the speed.
望远镜能让你看到三倍的速度。
Three times the magnification of the human eye.
人眼放大三倍。
OK? But it's not that great. But with this telescope, this new invention,
好的？不过不算太大。可是用这台新望远镜，
Galileo did amazing things.
伽利略做了惊人的事。
First thing he did was he discovered that Jupiter had moons.
第一件事是他发现木星有卫星。
And this was revolutionary because it was assumed that
这件事很革命，因为当时人们认为一切都围着地球转。
everything revolved around the planet Earth.
But now he showed that moons revolved around Jupiter.
但他现在证明了月球围绕木星转动。
He also recognized that,
他还意识到，
from the Earth, you're able to see Venus spin around us.
从地球上，你可以看到金星绕我们旋转。
And that also was revolutionary because it was assumed that
这件事也很革命，因为当时人们认为地球静止。
Earth stood still.
地球静止。
And all the planets stood still. OK?
所有行星静止。
So he wrote this book.
于是他写下了这本书。
And it was a sensation.
这本书一出即轰动一时。
He became like the core scientist to the Medici family.
他成了美第奇家族的核心科学家。
And the Catholic Church thought this book was great.
天主教会认为这本书很精彩。
OK? But the thing about Galileo, which is very important,
OK？但关于伽利略的事，最重要的是，
is that he was a very arrogant man.
他是个非常自负的人。
And because he was promoting the heliocentric model,
因为他在推广日心模型，
he was coming into conflict with a lot of academics that were extremely well established,
他与许多已久立的学者产生冲突，
who made their living off the heliocentric model.
这些学者靠日心模型谋生。
OK? So they had these arguments. And
OK？于是他们提出了这些论点。然后
Galileo's arguments were very limited.
伽利略的论点很有限。
Remember, this is a new idea.
记住，这是一种新思想。
It's not really supported by mathematics. It's not really supported by a lot of data.
它并没有得到数学的充分支持，也没有大量数据的佐证。
OK? So Galileo's entire logic was,
OK？于是伽利略的完整逻辑是，
I speak to God, I know the truth, and you're all idiots.
我向上帝宣言，我知真理，而你们都是傻瓜。
OK? That was basically how he spoke to his enemies.
OK？那基本就是他对敌人的说法。
And as you can imagine, he had more and more enemies.
正如你想象，他的敌人越来越多。
And as you can also imagine, his enemies were devising ways to get at Galileo.
你也能想象，他的敌人想方方办法来对付伽利略。
One thing that Galileo was saying privately
伽利略私下所说的其中一件事，
that he should not have been saying is that
他本不该说的那件事是，
people were saying to him, listen, this heliocentric model,
人们对他说：听着，这个日心模型，
it's fine, but it goes against Scripture.
好的，但这与经文相反。
OK? Let's look at Scripture. Scripture says that
好的？我们来看看经文。经文说，
the earth, it's firm and immovable.
地球是坚固不动的。
OK? That's what the Bible says.
好的？这就是圣经所说的。
Also, if you look at Genesis, it's clear that God created the earth first.
另外，如果你看创世记，清楚地表明上帝先造了地球。
And then he created the heavens, the sun and the moon and the stars.
随后他又造了天空、太阳、月亮和星星。
So logically,
于是，逻辑上，一切都应该围绕地球转动。
everything should revolve around earth.
于是，伽利略，你怎么解释地球与地球之间的冲突？
So, Galileo, how do you explain this conflict between the earth and the earth?
How do you explain this conflict between your theory of the heliocentric model and Scripture?
你如何解释你日心说与经书之间的冲突？
And Galileo's response was,
伽利略的回答是，
it's my job to interpret Scripture.
我负责解释经书。
And this, as you remember from last week, it's heresy.
而这点，正如上周所说，属于异端。
OK? If you disagree with the church, that's not heresy.
好？如果你与教会不合，那就不是异端。
That could just be ignorance.
这也许只是无知。
OK? But if you believe that you are above the church,
好的？但如果你认为自己高于教会，
if you refuse to accept the authority of the church, if you believe that I interpret the Bible, you're not a believer.
如果你拒绝接受教会的权威，若你认为我才是解经者，你就不是信徒。
You're not evangelical, that is heresy,
你不是福音派，属于异端。
that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical,
那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，
that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical,
那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，
that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical,
那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，那是福音派，
that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical,
那是福音派， 那是福音派， 那是福音派， 那是福音派， 那是福音派，
that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical, that is evangelical,
那是福音派， 那是福音派， 那是福音派， 那是福音派，那是福音派， 那是福音派， 那是福音派， 那是福音派，
that is evangelical,
那是福音派， 那是福音派， 那是福音派， 那是福音派， 那是福音派，
那是福音派，
promote your views anymore and because
再宣传你的观点吧，且因为
if you were guilty of heresy you could be brought the stake Galilee had no choice
如果你犯了异端，你就会被带到火焰上，伽利略也无选择
but to follow this order okay that
但按这个顺序来，好的，那个
is until 1632
到1632为止
what happened 1632 well the old Pope died
发生了什么，1632年，旧教皇去世
and the new Pope urban the eighth came to power
并且新教皇乌尔班八世登基
who is urban the eighth well he was a very good friend of Galileo's
乌尔班八世是个很好的伽利略朋友
and urban the eighth was a huge admirer of doubt of Galileo's okay
乌尔班八世非常欣赏伽利略的疑问
so Galileo felt he now had permission to get back at his enemies
于是伽利略觉得自己现在有机会再度过敌人
so he wrote a book called dialogue concerning the two chief world system
于是他写了一本名为《两大世界体系的对话》的书
and it was it was basically like almost like a platonic dialogue okay
基本上它像一场柏拉托式的对话
where he presented his argument again for the hill centric model not only
他再次阐述了山丘中心模型的论点，并且戏弄他的敌人，形成对话的形式
that but he made fun of his enemies so it's a dialogue
他又一次提出山丘中心模型的论点，并戏弄敌人，形成对话的形式
and
他再次提出山丘中心模型的论点，并戏弄敌人，形成对话的形式
the chief enemy of Galileo's name
伽利略的主要敌人是Simplicitous
was Simplicitous okay Simplicitous moron not only
Simplicitous是个简单的傻瓜
that but he put into the mouth of Simplicitous
他把这事说进了Simplicitous的嘴里
a lot of the arguments from Pope urban the eighth okay
大量来自乌尔班八世的论点
so he was making fun of the Pope even though they were very good friends so
于是他戏弄教皇，虽然两人关系很好
as you can imagine the Pope was really
正如你所想，教皇确实如此
pissed at first he banned this book and what happens
先是被气，随后他禁书，结果怎样？
when you ban a book you make it into a national bestseller okay
当你禁书时，它会变成全国畅销书，没错！
so everyone was reading this book so now he's banned this book and what happens is that he lost thatлилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилили
于是大家都在读这本书，结果他又禁书，结果就是……
thatлилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилили thatлилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилили thatлилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилили
thatлилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилили And so
那……于是
I wrote this book as
我写这本书是因为
an intellectual exercise to see how wrong it could be
一次知识性练习，看看它有多错误
and to see if it could be right.
再看看它有多正确
So saying things like this didn't work.
于是这样说并没有奏效。
And they basically put him under arrest.
于是他们基本把他关押了。
At this point, Gallaudet's friends pleaded with the Pope.
此时，Gallaudet的朋友们向教皇求情。
And the Pope said, fine, I'm a generous person.
教皇答道：好吧，我是个慷慷之人。
I will commute his sentence to house arrest for the rest of his life.
我将把他的刑期改为余生在家监禁。
So that is a story of Galileo.
于是这就是伽利略的故事。
So you can make the argument that
于是你可以这样论证
it was Galileo's personality
它是伽利略的个性
that was responsible for his trial
那是导致他受审判的原因以及他的衰败。是他的自负。
and downfall. It was his hubris.
It's a very classic Greek tragedy.
这是一出非常经典的希腊悲剧。
But historically,
但从历史上说，
that's not how we remember this story.
这并不是我们记住这段故事的方式。
The reason why is, again, remember, there's a major conflict between the Protestants and the Catholics.
原因是，正如前所述，正教与新教之间存在大冲突。
So the Protestants will use this trial as propaganda against the church.
于是新教将此审判作为对教会的宣传。
And the Protestants will say,
新教会说，
you see how anti -science the church is.
你会看到教会对科学的反感。
And Galileo will be remembered now as the father of modern science
而伽利略现在被记作现代科学之父，因他把科学置于宗教之上。
because he put science above religion.
And even though Galileo was disgraced during his time,
而且即使伽利略在当时被贬黜，
eventually what will happen is, the Florentines,
最终会怎样，佛罗伦蒂人，
the people of Florence, they will dig up his grave and
佛罗伦蒂人，他们会挖出他的坟墓
put his body beside Michelangelo and Dante.
把他的遗体放在米开朗和但丁旁边。
That's how much they revered the contribution of Galileo.
这就是他们对伽利略贡献的崇敬之深。
Again, even
再一次，甚至
though the theory of heliocentrism is correct,
虽然日心说是正确的，
the mathematics didn't make any sense.
数学却没能解释清楚。
At this time in history, if you had a team of scientists go
此时若有一组科学家去……
and look at, the geocentric argument versus the heliocentric argument,
并且看，地心说与日心说的对比，他们会说地心说更合理。
they would say the geocentric argument makes more sense.
好的？直到牛顿之前，……。
Okay? It was not until Newton,
Okay? It was notuntil Newton,
when the mathematics came into being,
当数学出现时，
that allowed for the heliocentric model to be widely accepted.
那使日心模型得到广泛接受。
Newton, as you know, he's the person who created calculus.
牛顿，正如你所知，他就是微积分的创始人。
The calculus you're learning in school, guess what?
你在学校学的微积分，猜猜是什么？
He was responsible for the creation of calculus.
他负责创立微积分。
Now what's really interesting for us, to me,
现在对我来说，真正有趣的是什么？
to know about Newton is,
了解牛顿的事，
Newton didn't really see himself as a mathematician or a scientist.
牛顿并不把自己视为数学家或科学家。
These were side hobbies. What he really was,
这些只是他的业余爱好。
was a theologian, okay?
他是位神学家，明白吗？
So he spent most of his time actually reading the Bible,
于是他大部分时间都在读圣经，
because he was convinced that reading the Bible were the secrets of the universe.
因为他确信读圣经就是宇宙的秘密。
Specifically, he wanted to know when the world would end.
具体来说，他想知道世界何时终结。
And he spent most of his life doing these calculations,
于是他把大半生涯用于这些计算。
and he told us that the world would probably end, I don't know, 2060, okay?
他告诉我们世界大概会在2060年终结，我不确定，2060年，明白吗？
2050, 2060, around then.
2050、2060，左右。
So he spent most of his time doing theology.
于是他把大半时间都用于神学。
This is important for us because,
这对我们很重要，因为，
even at this time, even as the scientific revolution is gaining steam,
即便在此时，科学革命正加速之际，宗教与科学尚未分离。
there is no separation between religion and science.
人们把信仰视为科学的根基。
People understood faith as a very important cornerstone of science.
People understood faith as a veryimportant cornerstone of science.
Without faith, how could you have the energy
没有信仰，你怎么能有那份能量？
and inspiration to understand the mind of God?
并且灵感去理解上帝之心？
Okay? Newton is also famous for being an alchemist.
好吧？牛顿亦以炼金术闻名。
So he spent most of his time also doing these science experiments,
于是他把大部分时间都花在做这些科学实验上，
where he's trying to combine different elements.
在那里他试图把不同的元素组合在一起。
Unfortunately, chemistry at this point, it's very primitive.
不幸的是，当时的化学还很原始。
So he was thinking mercury, okay?
于是他开始思考水银，嗯？
He was convinced that mercury will lead to the colossal stone, and he was eating it, he was tasting it.
他确信水银能引出巨石，他吃了它，尝了它。
And as a result, he had a lot of mercury poisoning problems.
于是他出现了大量水银中毒问题。
He couldn't sleep, he had delusions, his hair was falling out.
他睡不着，出现幻觉，头发掉落。
He had mercury poisoning, okay?
他患水银中毒，嗯？
But at the same time,
但与此同时，
he had the inspiration to come up with the mathematics to prove the heliocentric model is correct.
他灵感迸发，构思出证明日心说正确的数学。
The book he wrote is called the Principia.
他写的书叫《原理》。
At this time, Latin is the universal language of scientists,
此时拉丁语是科学家的通用语言。
right? And also, guys,
对吧？还有，大家，
at this time, they're not called scientists.
此时他们还不是叫科学家。
They're called natural philosophers.
他们叫自然哲学家。
All right?
好的？
Science is considered a part of philosophy.
科学被视为哲学的一部分。
All right, so in 1687,
好的，那么在1687年，
this debate ended with the publication of this book.
这场辩论以这本书的出版而告终。
Newton used mathematics
牛顿用数学
to prove once and for all
一次性地证明
the heliocentric model.
日心模型。
This is one page from the Principia.
这是《原理》中的一页。
As you can see, there are a lot of mathematics, there are a lot of diagrams, okay?
如你所见，里面有很多数学，也有很多图表，好的？
In this book, you also find his laws of motions.
在这本书里，你还会看到他的运动定律。
So Newton's great insight was that
于是牛顿的伟大发现是……
probably the laws of attraction,
大概是吸引定律，
gravity that govern this world,
引力支配着这世界，
probably govern the heavens as well, okay?
大概也支配着天体，
So before, it was assumed that the heavens and the earth were separate.
于是之前人们认为天与地是分开的。
And now he's saying that, no, these are combined together.
现在他又说，这些是组合在一起的。
And he created laws of planetary motion,
他还制定了行星运动定律，
okay? He figured out the mathematics
对吧？他搞懂了数学。
that told us the relationship between the size of the planets,
那告诉我们行星大小与质量以及它们轨道的关系，嗯？
the mass, and how they orbited, okay?
现在，问题是，他遇到了一个大问题。
Now, the problem though, he had a huge problem.
他有数学相关性，却不知道相关性为何存在。
The problem is he had the correlation,
问题是他有相关性，但不知道相关性为何存在。
he had the mathematical correlation, but he didn't know why the correlation existed.
他有数学相关性，却不知道相关性为何存在。
He couldn't solve the causation problem, okay?
他没能解决因果问题，嗯？
There's just no way that God would spend his time moving the planets around.
上帝怎么会把时间花在摆弄行星上呢？
He was much too busy. So there had to be an underlying cause.
他忙得很满，肯定有根本因。
He didn't know what it was though, okay?
但他自己却不知道那根因是什么。
And who figured it out? Well, Einstein figured it out, right?
谁算出来的？嗯，爱因斯坦算出来的，对吧？
So at this point, in 1905,
于是到了1905年，
we knew that
我们已经知道了
there was a correlation between the size of the planet
有一个与行星大小相关的关系，以及它的运动方式，没错吗？
and how it moved, okay?
还有重力。但我们不知道它为什么会这样。
And gravity. But we didn't know why.
And gravity. Butwe didn't know why.
And it was the genius of Einstein to figure it out.
于是爱因斯坦凭借天才算出来的。
Now, you remember Einstein because of his famous equation, right?
现在，你记得爱因斯坦是因为他的著名方程，对吧？
The equation E equals mc squared, okay?
方程是E=mc²，明白吗？
What does E equals mc squared mean?
E=mc² 是什么意思？
It means that mass and energy are correlated.
它意味着质量和能量相互关联。
And this is a revolution. We didn't understand this before, right?
这是一场革命。我们之前还没懂，对吧？
We just assumed that solids and vibrations are different.
我们只是假设固体和振动是不同的。
And what Einstein is saying is that
而爱因斯坦所说的是：
in order for a solid to exist, there have to be vibrations in the first place.
为了让固体存在，首先必须有振动。
And this formula tells us
而这公式告诉我们
that within all objects,
在所有物体中，
there is almost an infinite amount of energy, okay?
几乎有无限量的能量，好的？
Because c is the speed of light.
因为c是光速。
And why is this important?
那又为什么重要？
Because this formula will allow us to develop the nuclear bomb,
因为这个公式能让我们研制核弹。
right? By splitting an atom,
对吧？把原子拆开，
you can create almost an infinite amount of energy in this world,
你可以在这个世界里产生几乎无限量的能量，
okay? So that's a major contribution of Einstein.
好的？这就是爱因斯坦的主要贡献。
But at his time,
但在他那个时代，
he was mainly known for figuring out the causation problem in space, okay?
他主要以解决空间因果问题而闻名，好的？
And what... And
然后呢……
how Einstein figured it out is by developing a new idea called space -time.
恩斯坦是通过提出一个叫做时空的新概念来搞懂的。
He believed that in the heavens, there was a space -time curvature.
他认为在天空里有时空弯曲。
And so what was happening was this.
于是事情就是这样发生的。
A mass, a huge object,
一个质量，一个巨大的物体，
it would go into the space -time curvature and warp it.
它会进入时空弯曲并使其扭曲。
And because it warped it, it drew things into its orbit.
因为它扭曲了它，便把物体拉入轨道。
And then these things would have to move around this solid,
然后这些东西就得围着这块固体转动，
okay? So space -time curvature now helps us understand
好吧？于是时空弯曲现在帮助我们理解
the laws of planetary motion, first developed by Kepler and then by...
行星运动的规律，最先由开普勒提出，随后又由…
and then refined by Newton, okay?
然后被牛顿细化，好的？
And what's amazing about Einstein is...
而爱因斯坦的精彩之处是……
And this is like...
这就像是……
This will blow your mind, okay?
这会让你惊叹，好的？
But he did all this while
但他在这期间完成了这一切
sitting at a desk at a patent office in Switzerland.
坐在瑞士专利局的桌前
He was not in a laboratory. He was not at a university.
他不在实验室，也不在大学。
He was just thinking by himself.
他只是独自思考。
He was daydreaming, okay?
他在白日梦中，好的？
So this was just an incredible achievement.
于是这只是一次不可思议的成就。
Okay. And so the mathematics is very complicated, okay?
好了，数学很复杂，好的？
But all you need to understand is that he figured out
但你只需理解的是他搞明白了。
that there's a mathematical relationship between the mass of the object
对象的质量之间存在数学关系
and the space -time curvature, okay?
和时空曲率，好的？
And this formula tells us what the relationship is.
这个公式告诉我们关系是什么。
And the... And
而且……而且
why mathematics is important is it allows us to make predictions.
数学重要的原因是它让我们能做出预测。
And these predictions will tell us if the...
这些预测会告诉我们……
if the science actually works or not, okay?
如果科学真的有效与否，好的？
If the model, the theory makes sense or not.
如果模型、理论成立与否。
And so Einstein's theory of relativity,
于是爱因斯坦的相对论。
space -time curvature, it is one of the most successful models in history
时空弯曲，它是历史上最成功的模型之一。
because it predicts the black hole, okay?
因为它预测了黑洞，好吗？
The black hole is almost solid.
黑洞几乎是固体。
That is infinitely massive.
它的质量无限大。
And therefore, it attracts everything into it, and sucks everything into it, including light.
于是它把一切都吸进去，包括光。
Okay, so it predicts the idea of the black hole.
于是它预测了黑洞的概念。
And we discovered the black hole, all right?
我们发现了黑洞，没错吗？
So this confirms the theory of relativity.
这就证实了相对论的理论。
But the theory of relativity also predicts the Big Bang
但相对论也预言了大爆炸。
because space -time...
因为时空……
The idea of space -time is that space is in motion, right?
时空的概念是空间在运动，对吧？
That's why you have time, because it's in motion.
这就是时间的存在，因为它在运动。
Well, if it's in motion, then where did it start?
如果它在运动，那它是从哪里开始的？
There had to be, like, a starting point.
那一定有个起点吧。
And that's why scientists... Not Einstein.
这就是科学家们的想法……不是爱因斯坦。
Einstein was actually against the idea of the Big Bang.
爱因斯坦实际上反对大爆炸的概念。
But a lot of scientists believe that you need a Big Bang, okay?
但很多科学家认为需要大爆炸，行吗？
And so we have a working model of the Big Bang.
于是我们得到了大爆炸的工作模型。
The problem with this model
这个模型的问题在于……
is that there's actually a lot of evidence against this.
实际上有大量证据与之相反。
Okay, so there are two examples.
好了，下面给出两个例子。
The first example is, using the Hubble telescope,
第一个例子是，利用哈勃望远镜，世界上最先进的望远镜，现已在外太空中，我们发现实际上有星系。
the most advanced telescope in the world, which is now in outer space,
第二个例子是，利用哈勃望远镜，世界上最先进的望远镜，现已在外太空中，我们发现实际上有星系。
we've discovered that there are actually galaxies
第三个例子是，利用哈勃望远镜，世界上最先进的望远镜，现已在外太空中，我们发现实际上有星系。
that came before they were due, okay?
那些在它们到来之前出现的，明白吗？
So the idea of Big Bang is that it's this massive energy explosion,
大爆炸的概念是它是一场巨大的能量爆炸，随后星系才会形成。
and so the galaxies will develop later.
随后星系会在之后发展。
But our data tells us the galaxies came before,
但我们的数据告诉我们星系早在之前出现，
much earlier than we expected.
比我们预期的早得多。
That's the first thing. Second problem that
这就是第一个问题。第二个问题是
we have with the Big Bang model is that
我们用大爆炸模型得到的结果是
this universal expansion, it is not constant.
这个宇宙膨胀并不是恒定的
There are times when it actually speeds up, which makes no sense.
有时它实际上会加速，这一点很奇怪。
Why would it speed up, okay?
为什么它会加速，好的？
So this Big Bang model,
所以这个大爆炸模型，
a lot of scientists are now trying to reexamine it.
很多科学家现在正试着重新审视它。
Okay, the problem is, and this is a huge problem,
好的，问题是，这个问题很大，
is we don't have a better theory.
就是我们没有更好的理论。
And so to get around the problem of these mathematical inconsistencies,
于是为了解决这些数学不一致的问题，
in the model,
在模型里，
scientists create a new concept called dark energy.
科学家创造了一个叫暗能量的新概念。
Dark energy. Now you think to yourself, dark energy means we can't see it.
暗能量。现在你会想，暗能量就是我们看不见它。
No, that's not what it means, okay?
不，那不是它的意思，好的？
And you're like, well, dark energy means we can't measure it.
然后你说，嗯，暗能量就是我们测不出来的。
No, that's not what it means. Dark energy means we don't know what it is,
不，那不是它的意思。暗能量就是我们不知道它是什么。
okay? Doesn't mean it exists and we can't see it.
好的？并不意味着它存在且我们看不见它。
It just means we have no idea what it is.
它只是表示我们不知道它是什么。
We cannot explain why it exists.
我们无法解释它为何存在。
Why the Big Bang is expanding really fast at certain points
为什么大爆炸在某些点扩张得很快
and really slow at other points.
并且在其他点慢得很快。
And so we just say it must be dark energy, okay?
于是我们就说它一定是暗能量，行吗。
Does that make sense, guys? So dark energy is not something that you can't see.
那有道理吗，大家？所以暗能量不是你看不见的东西。
It's just something we don't have no idea what it is, okay?
它只是我们不知道它是什么的东西，行吗？
All right, so these are the theories, okay?
好的，以上就是这些理论，行吗？
But the person who was most responsible for the creation of the Simon method,
而最主要负责创立西蒙方法的人是……
his name is actually Francis Bacon.
他的名字实际上是弗朗西斯·培根。
And he spent his entire life promoting the idea of some processes
他把一生都投入到推广某些过程的理念上。
and methods.
和方法。
He's most well known for his book, The New Atlantis.
他最著名的书是《新亚特兰蒂斯》。
So in The New Atlantis,
于是，在《新亚特兰蒂斯》中，
which is like a novel, the protagonist,
就像一部小说，主角，
he ends up on an island where they have the most advanced science in the world.
他最终来到一个岛屿，那里拥有世界最先进的科学。
And the reason why they have the most advanced science in the world is
之所以拥有世界最先进的科学，是因为……
because they turn science into a bureaucracy, a very special bureaucracy.
因为它们把科学变成了一种官僚，特别的官僚。
So I'm not going to read all of it, all right?
所以我不打算读完，行吗？
But there are different offices,
但有不同的办公室，
different bureaucracies for different functions.
不同的官僚承担不同的职能。
So for example, we have three that try new experiments, such as themselves, think good.
例如，我们有三类尝试新实验的官僚，像自己一样，想得好。
These we call pioneers or miners, okay?
这些我们称为先驱或矿工，行吗？
So you have an office, a bureaucracy, specifically to do experiments,
于是你有一个专门做实验的办公室，专门的官僚，
which means that you have an office, a bureaucracy, specifically to come up with hypotheses,
于是你有一个专门提出假设的办公室，专门的官僚，
to ask questions, okay?
于是你有一个专门提问问题的办公室，专门的官僚，
Also, we have three that take care out of them,
另外，我们有三类负责把它们处理好，
direct new experiments of a higher level, higher light, more penetrating into nature than the former.
直接进行更高层次、更高光度、更深入自然的实验，
These we call labs. So
我们把它们称为实验室。
you have a team to actually audit these experiments
你有一个团队来实际审核这些实验，并找出改进的方法，行吗？
and figure out how to improve them, okay?
然后，最后我们有三类……
And then lastly, we have three that
And then lastly,we have three that
raise the former discoveries by experiments into great observations,
把前期实验发现提升为伟大的观察
axioms, and atherisms. These we call interpreters of nature.
公理与假设。我们把它们称为自然的解释者。
So these are theoreticians.
于是它们就是理论家。
They're the ones who will take this experimental data and
他们是将实验数据整理成理论的人。
combine it into a theory.
他们将这些实验数据合并成理论。
And so Bacon is proposing a scientific bureaucracy.
于是巴克提出了科学官僚制。
And guess what, guys? We have basically achieved his vision today.
猜猜看，大家？我们今天基本实现了他的愿景。
If you look at science today, it's essentially a bureaucracy,
如果你看看今天的科学，它基本上就是一个官僚制，
all right? Now,
好了，
one of the foundations of this bureaucracy was the
其中一个官僚制的基础是伦敦皇家学会的创立，1660年，好的？
founding of the Royal Society of London in 1660, okay?
Why is this important? Because for the first time,
为什么重要？因为这是第一次，
scientists are allowed to present their findings
科学家们被允许展示他们的研究成果
before a group of peers who will question and doubt them.
在一群同行面前，他们会提问并怀疑。
And this will enhance their research process,
这将提升他们的研究过程。
okay? So the founding of the Royal Society was fundamental.
好的？所以伦敦皇家学会的创立是根本的。
As you can imagine, what will come next is publications, magazines, that
正如你所想，接下来的是出版物、期刊，等将展示许多新发现。
will showcase a lot of these new discoveries.
will showcase a lot ofthese new discoveries.
The founding members of the Royal Society include Christopher Wren,
皇家学会的创始成员包括建筑师克里斯托弗·温恩，
who was a very famous architect. As well as Robert Dole,
以及化学家罗伯特·多尔。】
who was a very famous chemist.
Okay, so
好的，先说一下
that's a basic background into the history of the Second Revolution.
这就是第二次革命历史的基本背景
Today, we are asking ourselves a very deep question.
今天我们要问一个很深刻的问题
So the Second Revolution separated science from religion.
于是第二次革命把科学与宗教分离。
And there's a lot of concern that
而且人们对此有不少关注。
this has created a lot of ethical issues within science, okay?
这也在科学中产生了许多伦理问题，嗯。
So let's look at three major issues.
那么我们先看三个主要问题。
The first major issue is the idea of artificial intelligence.
第一个主要问题是人工智能的概念。
Basically, we're trying to create God.
基本上，我们正在尝试创造上帝。
And that's a huge concern.
于是这就成了一个大问题。
What happens when the computers are much smarter than humans?
当计算机远比人类更聪明时会怎样？
Okay? Second is the idea of nanotechnology, where
好吗？第二个是纳米技术的概念，在那里…
we're trying to go into the atomic level
我们正试图进入原子层面并改变自然法则，行吗？
and change the laws of nature, okay?
我们正试图挑战上帝。第三个是基因学的概念。
We're trying to defy God. And the third is the idea of genetics,
where we are trying to change people's genetic blueprints.
我们正试图改变人类的基因蓝图。
So that we can have designer babies, so that
于是我们可以造出定制的宝宝，随后…
babies will be free from cancer.
宝宝将摆脱癌症的束缚。
Also, we're trying to develop immortality, okay?
我们也在尝试开发不死之术，行吗？
We're looking for the elixir of immortality.
我们正在寻找不死之灵丹。
Okay, so these are three massive ethical debates within science.
好了，这三件事就是科学里的三大伦理争论。
And my argument to you today is that this is the wrong question to ask.
我今天的论点是，这个问题问错了。
Okay? This is the wrong question to ask.
好？这个问题问错了。
These are not... possible within the current scientific framework
这些在现有科学框架内并非可行。
that we have today. In fact, I would make the argument
我们今天有的那件事。实际上，我会说这三件事本质上是幻影。
that these three are essentially illusions.
咒语，魔法。
Hocus pocus, magic.
Or you can even go as far as to say they are deliberate scams.
或者你甚至可以说它们是有意的骗局。
So artificial intelligence is the example that
于是人工智能就是我们最熟悉的例子，好吗？
we are most familiar with, okay?
So I'm sure you've all used ChatGPT.
我很确定你们都用过ChatGPT。
Is it any good? No, it's not.
它好用吗？不，它不行。
Will it get any better? No, it won't.
它会更好吗？不，它不会。
Okay? So, but there's so much hype around it.
好的？所以，虽然它很受关注。
Okay? I don't have time to go into artificial intelligence,
好的？我没时间再聊人工智能，
but if you want to know more about artificial intelligence
但如果你想了解更多人工智能
and why it's a scam, I can do so later on, okay?
并且它是个骗局，我稍后再说，好吗？
Just ask me. All right.
只要问我就行。好。
So the real problem is this.
于是真正的问题是这个。
Okay, the real problem is this. Science has become an imperial bureaucracy.
好的，真正的问题是这个。科学已成为帝国官僚。
That's the real issue.
这才是核心问题。
All right? If you think about the world we live in today,
好了？如果你思考我们今天所处的世界，
the field that
该领域就是今天的科学，最像中国的帝国官僚。
is most like the imperial bureaucracy of China is science today.
科学高于民族。
Science is above nation.
Science is abovenation.
It is above government. It does things by itself, okay?
它高于政府。它自成其事，行吗？
And what's science doing?
科学在干什么？
Science is promoting its own bureaucracy.
科学正推动自己的官僚化。
If there's no accountability, if there's no responsibility,
如果没有问责，没有责任，
if scientists don't actually have to tell us what they're doing,
如果科学家们实际上不需要告诉我们他们在做什么，
then it's not that they will become God.
那么他们不一定会成为上帝。
It's more like they'll become corrupt bureaucrats.
它更像是他们会变成贪污的官僚。
Does that make sense? It's more likely that
这样说通吗？更可能的是……
they will take these billions of dollars the government's fraud them,
他们会把这些数十亿美元交给政府，政府再把它们骗走。
and they'll just waste it all. Okay?
然后他们就会把它们全都浪费掉。好吗？
Why? Because they can.
为什么？因为他们可以。
It's much easier for people to be lazy, greedy, and corrupt than it is for them to become God.
让人们懒惰、贪婪、腐败比成为上帝更容易。
Okay? All right.
好的？全部明白。
So let me explain.
接下来我来解释。
Okay. So I know this is a hard idea,
好的，我知道这很难懂。
but genius does not come from hard work.
但天才并非靠辛勤得来。
It does not come from some process or some method.
它不是来自某个过程或方法。
It comes from intuition,
它来自直觉。
imagination, and inspiration.
想象，灵感。
Okay? So remember when
好吧？记得当……
Einstein, he was just daydreaming his theories.
好吧？记得当爱因斯坦，他正白日梦想他的理论。
Okay? Remember when Newton,
好吧？记得当牛顿，
he was working on the first revolution.
他正在进行第一次革命的工作。
He was working on theology. He was working on alchemy.
他正在研究神学。正在研究炼金术。
And then he developed the ideas of calculus.
然后他发展了微积分的思想。
Okay? This is true consistently throughout history.
好吧？这在历史上一直如此。
This is a passage from the book The Cosmic Serpent by Jerry Narby.
这是杰里·纳尔比《宇宙之蛇》一书中的一段。
Okay? I'll just read it to you.
好吧？我先给你读一遍。
Many of science's central ideas seem to come from beyond the limits of rationalism.
科学的许多核心思想似乎来自理性之外的领域。
People do not logically deduce these ideas.
人们并不是用逻辑推演得到这些思想。
Rene Descartes dreams of an angel who
雷内·笛卡尔梦见一位天使，向他阐述宇宙的基本原理。
explains the basic principles of the universe.
这些思想如同流水般涌入。
These ideasлилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилилили
James Watson scribbles on a newspaper in a train,
詹姆斯·沃森在火车里在报纸上乱涂一笔，
then rides his bicycle to reach the conviction
随后骑自行车去验证他的信念
that DNA has the form of a double helix.
他相信DNA呈双螺旋形状。
So what gives rise to great science, to great ideas?
于是，是什么让伟大的科学诞生，伟大的思想诞生？
Well, imagination,
好吧，想象，
intuition, and also faith that you are correct, right?
直觉，还有对自己正确的信念，嗯？
That's Galileo. Galileo was actually convinced that he was right even
那是伽利略。伽利略确实确信自己是对的，尽管科学很粗糙。
though the science was very sloppy.
事实上有一个非常著名的故事，讲的是爱因斯坦，…】
In fact, there's a very famous story where Einstein,
in the 1930s and 40s, he was having a huge argument with scientists
在1930年代和1940年代，他与支持量子力学的科学家们展开了激烈的辩论，尤其是尼尔斯·玻尔。
who were arguing for quantum mechanics, specifically Niels Bohr.
去回顾1930年代和1940年代的辩论，你会看到那场争论。
Go and look back in the 1930s and 40s, and you look at the arguments.
Go and look back in the 1930s and40s, and you look at the arguments.
What you will find is that Einstein was very clear,
你会发现爱因斯坦非常清晰，
was very logical, and was very sound.
非常有逻辑，且非常可靠。
And you will find that Niels Bohr was unclear,
而你会发现尼尔斯·玻尔则不够清晰。
illogical, and very sloppy with his science.
不合逻辑，且科学上很散乱。
But Einstein was wrong, Niels Bohr was right.
但爱因斯坦错了，尼尔斯·玻尔对了。
Today quantum mechanics is a science that underlines all the technology
如今量子力学是一门支撑所有技术的科学。
that we have today, including the computer, the semiconductor, the transistor, the computer.
我们今天拥有的，包括电脑、半导体、晶体管、电脑。
So that's a really important thing we have to remember about science.
所以这就是我们必须记住的关于科学的一个非常重要的事。
At first, it seems wrong, but because the people who
起初看起来是错的，但因为那个人…
believe in it have so much conviction and faith, they eventually triumph.
相信它的人有如此多的信念与信心，最终会取得胜利。
So that's how science develops.
于是，科学便以此方式发展。
And this is the argument of Thomas Kuhn in his book,
这正是托马斯·库恩在其著作中的论点。
The Structure of Scientific Revolutions.
科学革命的结构
This is a book that I highly recommend.
这本书我极力推荐
If you ever study the history of science, this is the first book that you will read.
如果你曾研究科学史，这本书是你首先会读的
Because he goes into how science develops over the centuries.
因为他会讲述科学在几个世纪里是如何发展的。
The central argument is that science does not develop
核心论点是科学并不是逐步、缓慢、方法化地发展。
piecemeal and slowly and methodically.
It goes through revolutions and paradigm shifts.
它经历了革命和范式转变。
So, I know this is going to be a bit long,
所以，我知道这会有点长，
but it's really important that we read him, okay?
但我们读它真的很重要，行吗？
Paradigms gain their status because
范式之所以获得地位是因为
they are more successful than their competitors in solving a few problems
它们在解决一组从业者已认定为关键的问题时，比竞争者更成功
that the group of practitioners has come to recognize as acute.
而这些问题正是他们所关注的
So, Ptolemy, for his time, was considered revolutionary
于是，托勒密在他那个时代被视为革命性人物
because he saw the problem of why,
因为他探讨了为什么的问题
why is it the moon revolves around the Earth?
为什么月球绕地球转动？
Why is it the moon revolves around the Earth? Okay, he provided cosmology that was simple
为什么月球绕地球转动？好吧，他提供了简单的宇宙论，且符合神学。
and which fit into theology.
更成功的说法并非如此。
To be more successful is not, however,
to be either completely successful with a single
要么完全成功于单一问题，要么不成功于任何大数，好的？
problem or not successful with any large number, okay?
于是，托勒密的方案只解决了几个问题。
So, Ptolemy's solution only solved a few problems.
It was not the complete solution.
这并不是完整的解决方案。
The success of a paradigm is, at the start,
一个范式的成功，起初时是
largely a promise of success discoverable in selected and,
大部分是可在选定的...
still, incomplete examples.
仍然是未完成的例子。
Okay, so, the paradigm at first,
好的，所以，范式起初时，
it's actually promising, but it's not at all convincing.
它实际上是有前景的，但完全不够令人信服。
Normal science, okay, the science that we practice today,
普通科学，好的，今天我们实践的科学，
consists in the actualization of that
由此实现的就是那个
promise and actualization achieved by extending the knowledge of those facts
承诺的实现以及通过扩展对这些事实的认识所达到的实现
that the paradigm displays as particularly revealing by increasing
那种范式特别显现的地方在于它能把那些事实与范式的匹配程度提高到更高的层次。
the extent of the match between those facts and the paradigm.
于是，我们今天所实践的科学，不仅仅是关于范式的预测，更是关于进一步阐述范式本身的过程。
So, the science that we practice today, it's not just about the paradigm's predictions and by further articulation of the paradigm itself.
Okay, so, this is really important, guys.
好的，这个真的很重要，大家。
Science is not about discovery.
科学不是关于发现。
It's about refinement.
是关于精炼。
Does that make sense? Science will not give us new ideas.
这有道理吗？科学不会给我们新想法。
Science will take existing ideas and fine -tune them into something
科学会把已有想法拿来细调，变成我们能相信并用来推动技术创新的东西。
that we can believe and that we can use to drive technological innovation.
Okay? All right, so, let's look at another passage.
好的？好了，接下来我们再看一段。
Turn now to another more difficult and
现在转到另一段更难、更能体现两者并行的内容。
more revealing aspect of the parallelism between puzzles
more revealing aspect of theparallelism between puzzles
and the problems of normal science.
和普通科学的问题。
If it is to classify as a puzzle,
若要把它归类为谜题，
a problem must be characterized by more than an assured solution.
问题必须由不止于确定解的特征所表征。
There must also be rules that
也必须有规则
limit both the nature of acceptable solutions
限定可接受解的性质
and the steps by which they are observed.
以及它们被观察的步骤。
Accordingly, each of these rules,
因此，每条规则，
each of these problems, each of these problems, each of these problems, each of these problems, each of these problems, each of these problems,
每个问题，每个问题， 每个问题， 每个问题， 每个问题， 每个问题， 每个问题，
each of these problems, each of these problems,
每个问题， 每个问题，
each of these problems,
每个问题，
each of these problems, each of these problems,
每个问题，每个问题，
each of these problems,
each of
每个
these problems, the model much more elegant.
这些问题，模型更优雅。
It's not trying to reimagine the model,
它并不是在重新构想模型，
it's not trying to over -trim the model, it's not trying to add new pieces to the model,
它并不是在过度修剪模型，也不是在给模型加新块，
all it's doing is fine -tuning existing pieces.
它所做的只是对已有块进行微调。
It's like, you take a jigsaw puzzle,
就像你拿起一幅拼图，
and there's one, exactly one solution to the jigsaw puzzle,
还有一个，恰好只有一个拼图的答案，
if you don't provide that solution, you're wrong.
如果你没有给出那个答案，你就错了。
Okay, does that make sense? That's what science is.
好了，这样说通了吗？这就是科学的样子。
Nevertheless, such a picture would not be a solution, okay?
然而，这样的画面仍不是答案，行吗？
So what he's saying is, if you come up with a new picture to the jigsaw puzzle,
所以他的意思是，如果你给拼图来一幅新图，
you might be creative, you might be interesting,
你可能很有创意，也可能很有趣味。
you might be imaginative, but you're wrong, okay?
你可能很有创意，但你错了，行吗？
Scientists cannot accept your solution.
科学家们接受不了你的答案。
To achieve that, all the pieces must be used,
要做到这一点，所有拼块都要用上。
their plain sides must be turned down, and
它们的平面必须向下翻转，且
they must be interlocked without forcing until no holes remain, okay?
它们必须互锁，直到没有空隙为止，行吗？
Those are among the rules that govern jigsaw puzzle solutions.
这些是拼图解法的规则之一。
So if you are a scientist working today, you are literally
于是如果你是今天的科学家，你就像在拼拼图。答案，大家都知道答案。
solving a jigsaw puzzle. The solution, everyone knows the solution.
如果你提供的东西与已接受的答案相反，...
If you provide something that goes against the accepted solution,
you will not be accepted.
你将不会被接受。
Alright, so he concludes, but
好的，他得出结论，但
paradigm debates are not really about relative problem -solving ability,
范式辩论并非真正关于相对问题解决能力。
though for good reasons they are usually touted in those terms.
虽然有很好的理由，它们通常被这样称赞。
Instead, the issue in which paradigm should,
相反，范式应该在什么问题上展开，
in the future, guide research on problems
未来，范式将引导研究问题。
many of which neither competitor can yet claim to resolve completely.
其中许多尚未被任何竞争者完全解决。
A decision between alternate ways of practicing science is called for,
需要在不同科学实践方式之间做出决定，
and the circumstances that
以及相应的情况
this decision must be based less on
此决定应以未来潜力为主，而非过去成就。
past achievement than on future promise.
在早期接受新范式的人往往需要做…。
The man who embraces a new paradigm at an early stage must often do
so in defiance of the evidence provided by problem -solving, okay?
于是你要在问题解决所给出的证据面前逆行，好吗？
So this is hard for us to understand, but if you are to be a true innovator,
所以这对我们来说很难理解，但如果你要成为真正的创新者，
it's not that you come up with a new solution to a problem,
并不是说你要为一个问题提出新的解决方案。
it's that you must defy the basic premises
就是你必须突破基本前提
of bureaucratic science.
官僚科学的。
He must, that is, have faith that
他必须，也就是说，拥有信仰。
the new paradigm will succeed without many large problems
新的范式将会在没有太多大问题的情况下成功
that confront it, knowing only that
它只知道这些问题已被面对
the older paradigm has failed with few.
旧范式仅在少数情况下失败。
A decision of that kind can only be made on faith.
这类决定只能凭信仰作出。
Okay, so this is why it's almost impossible to separate religion from science.
好的，这就是为什么宗教与科学几乎无法分离的原因。
If a new discovery is to be made, that
如果要有新的发现，
person must believe that he is sent by God to tell us the truth.
人必须相信自己是上帝派来告诉我们真相的。
Okay, that's Galileo.
好的，就是伽利略。
Galileo, if you actually met the person, you would think that this guy's a complete asshole.
伽利略，如果你真的见过他，你会觉得这家伙真是个彻底的傻瓜。
Alright, he's arrogant, he's obnoxious.
好吧，他很自大，真是个讨人厌的家伙。
All he does is make fun of you. Okay, but
他所做的只是取笑你。好吧，接着说。
he's driven by a divine mission to spread the truth.
他被神的使命驱使去传播真理。
And because he created this conflict with the church,
因为他与教会产生冲突，于是引发了全国性的争论
it became a national controversy
并聚焦了科学家的注意力。
and that focused attention of scientists.
And that's why it's so important that that's a part of the and they try to resolve this issue.
于是这就是它重要的原因，正是它成为了那部分并且他们试图解决此问题。
Okay? So, science, scientific innovation,
好吧？所以，科学，科学创新，天才，它不是茶会，没错？
genius, it's not a tea party, all right?
It's a revolution. Okay,
它是一场革命。好吧，
so I'm going to summarize what we've discussed.
于是我要总结我们讨论的内容。
Okay? Because this was a lot.
好吧？因为这已经很多了。
But I want to summarize what we did.
但我想先总结我们做了什么。
So that you have a basic framework to understand
这样你就能有一个基本框架来理解
what I'm talking about.
我在说什么。
Because there'll be other classes on these topics.
因为后面会有其他章节讨论这些主题。
We'll be discussing quantum mechanics at a future date.
我们将在未来的时间里讨论量子力学。
So I want to make sure that
所以我想先确认一下。
we understand the argument.
我们理解了这个论点。
Okay, so our argument is this.
好的，所以我们的论点是这样。
For most of history,
在大部分历史中，
science was part of religion.
科学曾是宗教的一部分。
Okay? Science was about validating this religion.
好的？科学是用来验证这宗教的。
But this creates a problem we call confirmation bias.
但这就产生了我们称之为确认偏差的问题。
Confirmation bias. Meaning that
确认偏差。也就是我们只会关注支持我们主张的证据。
we will only look at evidence
我们只会看见支持我们主张的证据。
that supports our claims.
And we do this every single day.
我们每天都这么做。
Okay, we all want to be right, we all want to feel good, we all want to be confirmed
好了，我们都想对，想好，想被确认，想被世界验证。
and validated by the world around us.
and validated bythe world around us.
Okay? So,
好的？所以，
there's a very famous experiment called the Dunning -Kruger.
有一个非常著名的实验叫做Dunning-Kruger。
You've heard of this, right? Okay, Dunning -Kruger.
你听说过吗？好的，Dunning-Kruger。
The Dunning -Kruger experiment. So
达宁-克鲁格实验。于是
Dunning -Kruger were two American psychologists.
达宁-克鲁格是两位美国心理学家。
And they were teaching an undergraduate class of four new students.
他们正在给四名新本科生上课。
And they made these students do two things.
他们让这些学生做两件事。
The first thing is they made every student take an IQ test.
第一件事是让每个学生做一次智商测试。
Okay? And the second thing is they asked students how they think they did on
第二件事是让学生们说说他们觉得自己做得怎么样。
that IQ test. Were you in the top 5%?
那份智商测试。你排在前5%吗？
Or were you in the bottom 10%? Were you in the bottom 5%?
还是排在后10%？你排在后5%吗？
Were you average? Okay? And it turned out that
你是平均水平吗？结果是……
once they looked at all the results,
一旦他们查看所有结果，
not one student predicted his or her class ranking.
没有一个学生能预测自己的班级排名。
Those who did really well, the top 5%, it was pretty easy for them,
那些成绩真的很好的前5%，对他们来说很容易。
so they assumed it was easy for everyone.
于是他们以为每个人都很容易为前提。
Okay? So they underestimated their performance by about 10%.
好吧？于是他们把自己的表现低估了大约10%。
Those who did the worst didn't really know
那些做得最差的学生确实不懂。
what was asked of them.
他们被问到的事。
Okay? So they overestimated their performance.
好吧？于是他们高估了自己的表现。
In fact, those who got it most wrong were the worst students.
实际上，最错的人是最差的学生。
So maybe they were the bottom 10%, but they thought they were average.
于是他们可能是前10%，但他们认为自己是中等水平。
Okay? And what this tells us is this.
好吧？这告诉我们的就是这个。
Doubt, self -doubt, it's really the mark of genius.
疑问、自我疑问，真的是天才的标志。
Okay? If you're able to doubt yourself, if you're able to question yourself,
好吧？如果你能自我怀疑，若你能自我提问，
if you're able to self -reflect,
若你能自我反省，
that's a sign of an excellent student.
那就是优秀学生的标志。
Okay? In fact, the best sign of an excellent student.
好吧？实际上，优秀学生的最佳标志。
So the question then is, how do you take,
于是问题是，怎样做，
how do you bring doubt into science?
怎样把疑问带入科学？
What you do is you separate science from religion and
你所做的就是把科学与宗教分离，并且
you create a bureaucracy around
你在科学周围创建了一个官僚体系，
science in order to instill doubt in the scientific process.
以此在科学过程中注入疑问。
Okay? That's the solution proposed by Francis Bacon.
好吧？这是弗朗西斯·培根提出的解决方案。
And again, it is the most successful solution in human history.
再说一次，它是人类历史上最成功的方案。
All right? So the starting process is hypothesis,
好了？那么起始过程就是假设。
experiment, data analysis,
实验，数据分析，
okay, replication.
好了，复制。
Okay? Does that make sense?
好了？这有道理吗？
You have a hypothesis. You then test it out.
你有一个假设。然后你去检验它。
If it works, according to data, you then have to replicate the experiment to make sure
如果它有效，按数据，你就得再复制实验以确认无误。
that you are correct.
这样就能确保你是正确的。
Now, the beauty of this model is that you can actually,
现在，这个模型的美妙之处在于你可以把它真正做成一个官僚体系，对吧？
you can actually make it into a bureaucracy, right?
于是每个部门都各自完成自己的工作。
So each department does its own thing.
这样就能把它真正做成一个官僚体系，对吧？
And so what happens is that
于是发生的事是……
each department is inspecting
每个部门都在检查……
and auditing the work of the previous department to make sure the results are accurate
并审计前一部门的工作以确保结果准确
and correct. Okay?
并且正确。好吗？
Does that make sense? And it turns out if you do it this way,
这有道理吗？结果是，如果你按这种方式做，
well, it's revolutionary.
好吧，真是革命性的。
And it explains the world that we live in today.
它解释了我们今天所处的世界。
It explains why scientific progress has been so fast
它解释了过去三四百年科学进步如此迅速的原因。
and so remarkable these past 300, 400 years.
它解释了过去三四百年科学进步如此显著的原因。
Okay? But embedded in the system
好的？但嵌在系统里
are lots and lots of other issues.
有很多很多其他问题。
Okay? Which I will discuss.
好的？我会讨论的。
The first is the idea of political control. It takes a lot of resources to run the system.
第一点是政治控制的概念。运行系统需要大量资源。
And as a result, you can allow politicians to come in and interfere with the science.
于是，政治家可以介入并干预科学。
Okay? That's the first problem. Second problem is that
好吧？这就是第一个问题。第二个问题是……
over time, each department will overspecialize.
随着时间推移，各个部门会出现过度专业化。
Okay? You have overspecialization, which means
好吧？你有过度专业化，这意味着……
that these departments are now unable to communicate with each other
于是这些部门现在无法相互沟通。
because the underlying assumptions,
因为基础假设，各个部门的科学会各不相同。
the science of each department will be different.
好吧？所以如果你做实验，就会用到很多仪器。
Okay? So if you run experiments, well, you use a lot of instruments.
好吧？这就是第二个问题，过度专业化。
Okay? All these instruments are so complicated
好吧？这些仪器太复杂，普通科学家不太懂你在做什么。
that normal scientists don't really understand what you're doing.
好吧？所以这就是第二个问题，过度专业化。
Okay? So that's the second problem, overspecialization.
Okay? So that's the secondproblem, overspecialization.
The third problem is
第三个问题是
the idea of accountability.
责任感的概念。
Okay? How do you know
好吧？你怎么知道？
if each department is doing a good job or not?
如果每个系部都做得好还是不行？
Right? You can't because now they're overspecialized.
对吧？现在他们过度专业化，没法做到。
The word we use is they are now aloof.
我们用的词是他们现在很疏离。
Okay? So there are many problems with this system.
好的？所以这个系统有很多问题。
Another problem is insularity, meaning that
另一个问题是孤岛化，意味着……
you have to spend like 20 years in
你需要花大约20年时间……
school before you can even enter the system.
学校在你能进入系统之前。
Okay? Insularity creates gatekeeping, which
好？孤岛化产生门槛，且…
means that only if you play by the rules,
这意味着只有按规则行事时，
only if you vet it, can you enter the system.
只要你检验它，你就能进入系统。
Okay? And as a result,
好？于是如此，
you no longer have any creativity.
你就不再有任何创造力。
So this is the great irony of science.
于是这就是科学的伟大讽刺。
Um, science was initiated,
呃，科学的起始，
inspired by the genius of Galileo,
受伽利略天才的启发，
Newton, and Einstein.
牛顿与爱因斯坦。
But today, science has developed to a point where
但如今，科学已发展到一个阶段，
it no longer welcomes
它不再欢迎
Galileo, Newton, or Einstein.
伽利略、牛顿或爱因斯坦。
Okay? Why? Because Galileo is an asshole.
好吧？为什么？因为伽利略是个混蛋。
He doesn't get along with other people.
他和别人不合拍。
They wouldn't let him in. Newton is crazy,
他们不让他进去。牛顿很疯狂，
right? He's alchemist. He believes that the Bible will reveal the end of the world.
对吧？他是炼金术士。他相信圣经会揭示世界末日。
He's crazy. They won't let him in.
他很疯狂。他们不让他进去。
Einstein is really bad at mathematics.
爱因斯坦数学真差。
He would fail all these mathematics tests in order to get into the system.
他会为了进入系统而把所有数学考试都考砸。
He probably would not get into graduate school today.
他今天可能还进不了研究生。
Right? So this is the world we live in.
对吧？这就是我们生活的世界。
So don't worry about artificial intelligence.
所以别担心人工智能。
Don't worry about billionaires living forever.
别担心亿万富翁永生。
Don't worry about nanotechnology.
别担心纳米技术。
Worry about the fact that we've come to a point in our civilization
要担心的是，我们的文明已到达某一点。
where we are now incapable of innovation.
我们现在已失去创新能力。
Okay? All right.
好的？那就行。
So that's it. Any questions?
好了，就是这样。有什么问题吗？
Okay. Okay.
好的。好的。
When you set up this lecture,
当你准备这场讲座时，
you talked about pre -modern science and...
你谈到了前现代科学以及……
You relied on intuition and faith and imagination.
你依靠直觉、信仰与想象。
I was really getting ready to push back on you and say, hey,
我正准备反驳你并说，嗨，
that's a lot of what the science, like modern science creates.
这正是科学，像现代科学所创造的很多东西。
And you brought that in, you know,
而你也把它带进来了，你知道，
very nicely to come to the later stages of the lecture
非常顺利地进入讲座的后期阶段
that inspired it.
那激发了它。
Okay. Well, thank you.
好的。谢谢。
Yeah, yeah. Thank you. Great.
好的，好的。谢谢。很棒。
Any questions?
还有问题吗？
Okay. Okay. That's fine. Okay.
好的。好的。没问题。好的。
So... I've got a light question.
好...我有个小问题。
Okay. Great. I didn't know about Newton's predictions about the end of the world,
好的，很好。我不知道牛顿关于世界末日的预测，
but if you're saying 2050, 2060,
但如果你说的是2050、2060，
what do you think the chances are that he was right?
你觉得他正确的几率是多少？
Okay. Okay.
好的。好的。
So, Newton. Okay.
所以，牛顿。好的。
So, what do we know that Newton...
那么，我们知道牛顿……
Okay. That Newton predicted the end of the world?
好的。就是牛顿预测世界末日？
Okay. The reason why is this.
好的，原因是这样。
So, Newton didn't have any family.
于是，牛顿没有家人。
He didn't have a wife. He didn't have any children.
他没有妻子，也没有子女。
So, his entire estate was left to his nephews and his nieces.
于是，他的全部财产留给了侄子侄女。
And Newton also left him a lot of money.
牛顿也给他留下了不少钱。
Okay. These are aristocrats.
好的。这些人是贵族。
Newton is actually the first commoner,
牛顿实际上是第一位平民。
the first non -royal in English history to receive a state funeral.
英国历史上第一位非王室人士获得国葬。
He's the first commoner to be buried at Westminster Abbey.
他是第一位在威斯敏斯特大教堂安葬的平民。
Okay. So, it was a very big deal back then.
好的。所以，那时这件事很大。
And his relatives obviously were aristocrats.
他和他的亲戚显然是贵族。
But the thing about aristocrats is that over time, they become poor.
贵族的事儿是，随着时间推移，他们会变得贫穷。
And what do you do when you become poor?
你一变穷了，干嘛？
Well, you sell off what is valuable.
好吧，你把有价值的东西卖掉。
And so, Newton's papers,
于是，牛顿的手稿，
all his notes
他所有的笔记
were auctioned off in, like, I think the 1930s.
在1930年代左右拍卖出去。
I don't remember, okay?
我不记得了，行吗？
1930s. And you would imagine that...
1930年代，你会想……
Everyone would want these notes, right?
大家都想要这些笔记，对吧？
Because, like, they reveal genius to you.
因为它们能让你看到牛顿的天才。
But for whatever reason, they didn't really sell very well.
但不知为何，它们卖得不太好。
And the sale was so
而且销售情况很糟，拍卖也很糟，结果分批出售。
bad, the auction was so bad, that it was sold piecemeal.
好的？还有一个人……
Okay? And one person who
bought the notes was John Keynes,
买下笔记的是约翰·凯恩斯，经济学家。
the economist. John Keynes, the economist.
约翰·凯恩斯，经济学家。
And he was so excited to read the papers of Newton.
他对读牛顿的论文兴奋不已。
He was like, oh, my God. There must be so
他当时说，哦，我的天啊。一定有这么多数学在这些论文里，能引出新的发现，对吧？
much mathematics in these papers that will lead to new discoveries, right?
于是他真正读这些论文时，...
So when he actually read the papers,
he was absolutely aghast at what he discovered.
他发现后，完全惊呆了。
It was alchemy. It was theology. And so
它是炼金术。它是神学。于是……
what Newton was trying to do was he was trying to read the Bible
牛顿所做的，就是读圣经。
and look for a secret code.
并寻找一个秘密代码。
I mean, he was crazy, okay?
我的意思是，他很疯狂，行吗？
Look for a secret code within the Bible that would tell him the future.
在圣经里寻找一个能告诉他未来的秘密代码。
And he was actually convinced.
他也确实相信。
I was trying to call... The Second Coming.
我正试着叫……第二次降临。
He was convinced that Jesus will return.
他确信耶稣会再来。
These are all Christians at this point, right?
这些人到此时都是基督徒，对吧？
He was actually convinced that Jesus will return.
他确实确信耶稣会再来。
And so he wanted to know when he would return
于是他想知道耶稣何时再来。
and how he would return.
并且他将如何归来。
Okay? So I think he made the prediction 2060.
好的？所以我认为他预测的是2060年。
But I can't be sure.
但我不确定。
But he made a prediction when the world would end.
但他预测了世界何时结束。
What's more important for us is that he became what we know...
更重要的是，他成为了我们所说的……
What we call a Christian Zionist.
我们所说的基督教犹太复国者。
Okay? The idea of a Christian Zionist,
好的？基督教犹太复国者的概念，
and this is really important, is that
这点真的很重要，
once you predict the future
一旦你预测未来并知道耶稣何时归来，你就想知道他是怎样归来的。
and you know when Jesus is returning, you want to know how he returns.
And Newton became absolutely convinced that
而牛顿也完全确信
for Jesus to return,
为了耶稣归来，
certain conditions had to be met in order to facilitate his return.
必须满足若干条件，才能促成他的归来。
One major condition was the return
其中一个主要条件是回归。
of the Jews to Jerusalem.
把犹太人送回耶路撒。
Because at this point,
因为此时，
Jerusalem was being controlled by the Ottomans.
耶路撒正被奥斯曼人控制。
Okay? He was absolutely convinced that we had to get all the world's Jews and return them to Jerusalem.
他完全确信我们必须把全世界的犹太人送回耶路撒。
Okay? Only problem was, Jews didn't want to go back.
好的？唯一的问题是，犹太人不想回去。
Okay? And so I think Newton,
好的？于是我想，牛顿，
and this is completely unknown about him.
这件事关于他的事完全未知。
Okay? He's actually one of the founders of a movement called Christian Zionism.
好的？他实际上是基督教犹太复国运动的创始人之一。
Let's figure out how to get all the Jews to go back to Jerusalem
让我们想办法把所有犹太人送回耶路撒。
and this will start a process which
这将启动一系列过程。
will culminate with the return of Jesus.
将以此为高潮，耶稣归来。
Okay? So
好吧？于是……
that's Newton.
那就是牛顿。
What this tells us...
这说明了什么……
And this is also something that is really important is
而且这件事也很重要：……
that he was part of a secret society with John Locke
他是与约翰·洛克一起的秘密社团成员
and some other really important individuals.
以及其他一些非常重要的人物。
And a secret society...
又有一个秘密社团……
I mean... like they were considered they consider themselves the true church right
我的意思是……他们自认为是真正的教会。
so Newton in his notes was very clear he fought the
于是牛顿在笔记中写得很清楚，他打败了……
Holy Trinity was nonsense there's only one God okay
圣三位一体是胡说，只有一位上帝，好的……
and he was the representative of God on earth he was here on a divine mission
他是地上上帝的代表，肩负神圣使命
so he's part of the secret society to try to achieve Christian Zionism
于是他成为秘密社团的一员，致力实现基督教犹太复国主义
and to discover when the second coming will happen
并试图预知第二次降临之时机
so he makes his prediction 2060 so
于是他预测2060年
when so whether or not Newton is correct that's not the issue the issue is
当时，牛顿是否正确并不是重点，重点是他用自己的力量和影响力在英格兰大力推广基督教犹太复国主义。
that with his power with his influence he
他用自己的力量和影响力在英格兰大力推广基督教犹太复国主义。
was heavily promoting Christian Zionism in England
and as we know what happened is these
以及正如我们所知，发生的事是这些
people will go to America okay a lot of these people
人们会去美国，好吧，很多这些人
who are Christian Zionist they will go to America believing
他们是基督教犹太复国主义者，去美国时相信
that America is the new Jerusalem well and then
美国是新的耶路撒，接着……
what happened later on is the
随后发生的事是……
Zionist Christian Zionist will link up
基督教犹太复国主义者会联手……
and they will plot to you know what happens later on is the Zionist Christian Zionist will link up and they will plot to
他们会策划，后面发生的事是基督教犹太复国主义者联手，他们会策划……
bring the Jews back to Jerusalem
把犹太人送回耶路撒
and this and this leads to something called the Balfour Declaration right
这和这导致了被称为巴尔福宣言的事
which is to say that after World War one when
这就是说，第一次世界大战后，奥斯曼帝国被击败，英国帝国……
the Ottoman Empire was defeated the British Empire
……现在允许全世界的犹太人……
now gives permission to all the Jews in the world to
return to Jerusalem whether or not they want to okay
回到耶路撒，无论他们是否愿意，好的
so this is why history is so important because
所以这就是历史重要的原因，因为
you cannot possibly understand what's happening in the Middle East today
你无法完全理解今天中东的局势
but first understanding what's happening in all this history all right
但先先理解这段历史到底发生了什么，行了
so does that
那这样说对吗
make sense okay all
有道理吗
right great
好的，太棒了
well well
嗯，嗯
again okay so so
再说一次，好吧
2060 again that's not the issue the issue is
2060 再说一次，这不是问题，问题是
that there are very powerful people in this world who
有些人在这个世界里非常有势力，他们相信这件事，另有一人也相信
believe in this and one who believe that
believe in this andone who believe that
it is divine mission to make this come true do you
它是神圣使命，让这件事成真，你呢？
stock power to use your influence you use some money
你用股权来发挥影响力，你用点钱来实现这预言吧？
to make this prediction come true it's
not really a prophecy okay
不算是真预言，刚好
it's really a plan this is
它真的是个计划，这个是
what it is a plan it's like how do we bring back Jesus
它的计划是怎样把耶稣带回去
because when Jesus returns the world ends and
因为耶稣归来，世界就结束了，且
everyone's happy okay that's heaven comes on earth but
大家都很开心，好的，天国降临人间，但
how do we make it happen well here's the plan Christian Zionism all right
我们怎么让它发生呢？好吧，计划是：基督徒犹太复国
so that's that's that's that's my real concern whether or not it the world ends in 2016 I don't know okay
所以这就是我的真正关心，世界在2016年会不会结束，我不知道，好吗
but the fact that
但事实是
there are really powerful people of the statue of Isaac Newton with like almost unlimited resources
有些人确实拥有像艾萨克·牛顿那样的强大地位，几乎无穷资源
and unlimited power they actually believe in this
并且拥有无限力量，他们实际上相信这一点
and they want to make this come true that
他们想让这一点成真
should be the major
应该是主要的关心点
concern right okay
好吗
so I apologize for for going out on this tangent okay
所以我为这点离题道歉，好的。
but so we don't have class on Thursday you
于是周四没上课。
but next Tuesday we'll start the age of exploration okay
但下周二我们将开始探索时代，好吗